yes, that's the problem
はい、それが問題です
OK
OK
because it can get from us to here
私たちからここまで届くから
that we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
but we can't see
でも私たちには見えない
Can
できる
OK, OK
はいはい
OK
OK
You've been therefore, so long, you have been standing in your송.
したがって、あなたは長い間、自分の立場に立っていました。
Please put your phone on silent to remind you that this presentation is in progress
このプレゼンテーションが進行中であることを知らせるために、携帯電話をサイレントにしてください
Wear a mask all the way and prohibit eating and drinking videos and audio recordings
マスクの常時着用、飲食禁止・動画・録音禁止
Do not use the flash when taking pictures
写真を撮るときはフラッシュを使用しないでください
Thank you for your cooperation
ご協力ありがとうございます
Also in order to make our event better
また、イベントをより良いものにするために
Need your valuable opinion
貴重なご意見が必要です
Please use the wireless network at the venue
会場では無線LANをご利用ください
please stop here
ここで止めてください
Scan event QR code
イベントQRコードをスキャン
Help us fill out the online questionnaire
オンラインアンケートへの記入にご協力ください
After confirming the completed screen to the off-site service desk staff
完成した画面を社外サービスデスクスタッフに確認後
You can get a beautiful small etiquette
ちょっとしたプレゼントがもらえる
Thanks
ありがとう
110 years of Academia Sinica
中央研究院110年
111 Years of Knowledge Feast
111 年にわたる知識の饗宴
Dean Zhu Jiahua
朱家華院長
Science Lecture Begins
理科の講義が始まります
Vice President Zhou Meiyin is invited to host
周美音副総統が主催者として招待される
Academician Li, distinguished guests and colleagues, good night everyone
李院士、来賓の皆様、同僚の皆様、おやすみなさい、皆さん
Welcome everyone to join our knowledge feast today
今日の知識の饗宴への皆様の参加を歓迎します
Dean Zhu Jiahua's popular science lecture
朱家華院長柯普講座
This year is Zhu Jiahua Gu's 130-year-old list
今年は朱家華九の130年前のリストです
Every year we hold commemorative Cope Lectures
記念コープ講座を毎年開催しています
express our condolences and respect
お悔やみと敬意を表します
When Dean Zhu signed the table in this hospital
朱学部長がこの病院でテーブルに署名したとき
In a situation of considerable shortage of resources and funds
資源と資金が大幅に不足する状況の中で
Establishment of a new residence in Nangang
南港に新居を構える
Then rebuilt the Institute of Plants, Institute of Chemistry and Institute of Zoology
その後、植物研究所、化学研究所、動物研究所を再建
Jingshi Institute and Democracy Institute were also built
京市研究所と民主研究所も建設された
For the development of the college's wishes and academics
大学の願いと学問の発展のために
Talent cultivation has laid a solid foundation
人材育成が強固な基盤を築いた
So today our lecture
それで今日の私たちの講義は
Special invitation to National Tsing Hua University
国立清華大学への特別招待
Li Dingguo Distinguished Research Chair Professor, Department of Physics
Li Dingguo 物理学科特別研究主任教授
He is an academician of the Mathematics Group of our college
彼は私たちの大学の数学グループの学者です
come and speak for us
来て私たちのために話してください
Academician Li is a Bachelor of Physics from National Taiwan University
李学士は国立台湾大学で物理学の学士号を取得しています。
Ph.D., Department of Physics, Brown University, USA
米国ブラウン大学物理学科博士号取得
at CUNY and UC
ニューヨーク市立大学とカリフォルニア大学で
postdoctoral research
博士研究員
He was from 1982 to 1996
彼は1982年から1996年まで在籍していた
Taught in the Department of Physics, Virginia Polytechnic University
バージニア工科大学物理学科で教鞭をとる
America against China in 1996
1996年のアメリカ対中国
Institute of Physics
物理学研究所
Also from 2012 to 2018
こちらも2012年から2018年まで
Acting as the director of the Institute of Physics
物理学研究所の所長を務める
Academician Li is a
李学者は、
a well-known physicist
有名な物理学者
Lin Yushi in Ningtai theoretical many-body physics
寧台理論多体物理学における林裕士
His greatest contribution was to propose the theory
彼の最大の貢献は理論を提案したことだった
Explain the special physical phenomenon of high temperature superbody
高温超天体の特殊な物理現象を説明する
It is all caused by the strong optical connection of electrons.
それはすべて、電子の強力な光学的結合によって引き起こされます。
So today he will introduce us to
そこで今日は彼が私たちに紹介します
This group behavior in this heart camp
このハートキャンプにおけるこの集団行動
he got many awards
彼は多くの賞を受賞した
Contains the 2003 National Science Council Distinguished Research Award
2003 年米国学術会議特別研究賞を含む
2005 Hou Jindui Distinguished Honor Award
2005年 ホウ・ジンドゥイ栄誉賞
With the 2019 Special Contribution Award of the Taiwan Physical Society
台湾物理学会の2019年特別貢献賞を受賞
He is a Fellow of the American and British Physical Societies
彼はアメリカとイギリスの物理学会のフェローです。
Elected as a Fellow of the Academy in 2018
2018年にアカデミーのフェローに選出
During service in Taiwan
台湾勤務中
He was from 2004 to 2006
彼は2004年から2006年まで
In charge of the Nano-National Technology Project
ナノ国家技術プロジェクト担当
kind of subject
主題の種類
Promoted from basic science to industrial application
基礎科学から産業応用までを推進
Core Facility Sharing
コア設備の共有
Various development plans to talent cultivation
人材育成までの多彩な開発プラン
so today we are very happy
だから今日はとても幸せです
Academician Li
李学術研究員
For us from the title of this speech is
このスピーチのタイトルから私たちにとっては、
From quantum to classical physics
量子から古典物理学へ
limited group behavior
限られた集団行動
this is what we are looking forward to
これが私たちが楽しみにしていることです
with this brilliant speech
この素晴らしいスピーチで
So we now welcome Academician Li with applause
それでは、李アカデミー会員を拍手をもって歓迎いたします。
we are
私たちです
Thank you Vice President Zhou for the invitation
周副総統のご招待に感謝します
His introduction is greatly appreciated
彼の紹介は大変感謝しています
Vice President Zhou can invite me to come today
周副主席が今日私を招待してくれるかもしれません
This is the list of all Dean Zhu Jiahua
朱佳華学部長のリストはこちら
To have this opportunity to remember him with him
彼と一緒に彼のことを思い出すこの機会を持つために
In fact, the reason why I am very happy is that
実際、私がとても嬉しい理由は、
In addition to my Academia Sinica for more than 20 years
20年以上中央研究院に加えて
It was Master Chang Ang's bribery and Dean Zhu Quan's
それはマスター・チャンアンの賄賂と朱全学部長の賄賂でした。
outside of help
助けの外で
sorry
ごめん
Apart from the help of Dean Zhu Quan
朱泉学部長の助けを除けば
Besides, I actually have some other connection with him.
それに、実は私と彼には別の因縁があるのです。
This correlation is the physical problem I want to talk about today
この相関関係が今日話したい物理的な問題です
Then this correlation is that Dean Zhu Jiahua’s nerve is Sun Yat-sen University
したがって、この相関関係は、朱家華学部長の神経は中山大学であるということになります
Di Zixi, this is not Sun Yat-sen University in Kaohsiung
迪子熙、ここは高雄の中山大学ではありません
Sun Yat-sen University in Guangzhou
広州の中山大学
Of course, his disciple Xi Xi is called the play director and vice principal.
もちろん彼の弟子のシーシーは劇監督と副校長と呼ばれています
Headmaster for many years
校長先生は長年
why did i mention this in particular
なぜこれを特に言及したのか
Because my father-in-law, Principal Zhou Fengqi
なぜなら私の義父、周鳳琦校長だからです。
Also graduated from Sun Yat-Sen University
中山大学も卒業
Actually he
実は彼は
My father-in-law and his family are in business in Guiyang
私の義父とその家族は貴陽で商売をしています。
His reasons for doing education
彼が教育を行う理由
In fact, it was inspired by Dean Zhu
実際、これは Dean Zhu からインスピレーションを得たものです
Dean Zhu especially encouraged him to engage in education
朱学部長は特に教育に従事するよう奨励した
So he held it in Guiyang and started to organize
そこで彼は貴陽でそれを開催し、組織化を始めました。
When I was in middle school for a while, I was fighting
中学生の時、一時期喧嘩してた
run a temporary middle school
仮設中学校を運営する
In fact, a lot of money
実は、たくさんのお金が
It was run with money from their own family business.
彼ら自身の家業からの資金で運営されていました。
This is what I think his whole life
これが彼の生涯を通して私が思うことです
are contributing to education
教育に貢献している
student development
生徒の成長
I think it is worthy of my admiration
それは賞賛に値すると思う
I personally appreciate this of course
もちろん個人的にはこれに感謝しています
Dean Zhu's contribution to this education
朱学部長のこの教育への貢献
There is a very big effort to contribute to Taiwan's education
台湾の教育に貢献するために非常に大きな取り組みが行われています
I have many classmates now
今ではたくさんの同級生がいます
In fact, it was Chiayi Middle School back then.
実は、当時は嘉義中学校でした。
against Taichung No. 1 Middle School
対台中第一中学校
My father-in-law was the principal at the time
義父は当時校長だった
so i think it's a great opportunity
だから素晴らしい機会だと思う
I'll also talk a little bit
私も少しお話します
Some thoughts on my research
私の研究についてのいくつかの考え
The topic I chose today is of course a bit strange
今日選んだテーマはもちろんちょっと変わったものです
because when I'm thinking about something
なぜなら、何かを考えているとき
I remember several students came to ask me
何人かの学生が私に尋ねに来たのを覚えています
What aspect of current physics research should be done
現在の物理研究のどのような側面を行うべきか
Of course it's a big problem
もちろん大問題ですよ
important question for students
学生にとって重要な質問
Which aspect of research is better
研究のどの側面が優れているのか
So I probably thought about it a little bit myself
だから自分でも少しは考えたのかもしれない
what were those highlights of my past research
私の過去の研究のハイライトは何でしたか
I just realized that I will give two examples today
今日は例を 2 つ挙げることに今気づきました
The problem I'm mainly working on is of course related to this
私が主に取り組んでいる問題は、もちろんこれに関連しています
This collective behavior is group behavior
この集団行動は集団行動です
This emerging means
この出現の意味は、
Forever limited in Chinese translation of this word is a bit complicated
永久に制限されるこの単語の中国語訳は少し複雑です
It is related to the emerging behavior called eternal limit
それは永遠の限界と呼ばれる新たな行動に関連しています
In particular I want to get two examples
特に 2 つの例を取得したいと思います
Of course, it has something to do with quantum and classical
もちろん、それは量子と古典と何らかの関係があります
The most important question to think about
考えるべき最も重要な質問
This is the season 19 to 24 from the beginning
最初からこれはシーズン19から24です
Of course physics has made great progress
もちろん物理学は大きく進歩しました
especially when most of us
特に私たちのほとんどが
We already know these important equations
私たちはこれらの重要な方程式をすでに知っています
Everyone knows the Maxual Equation
誰もが知っている最大方程式
Of course, this is very important for the current IT industry
もちろん、これは現在のIT業界にとって非常に重要です
All of these are included under the Maxual Equation
これらはすべて最大方程式に含まれています
With this photoelectric conduction all problems
この光電伝導によりすべての問題が解決されます
probably can understand
おそらく理解できる
Just use it in different occasions, in different ways
さまざまな機会、さまざまな方法で使用してください
But another fact, of course we also know about quantum mechanics
しかし、もう一つの事実、もちろん、私たちは量子力学についても知っています
The Schrodinger equation
シュレディンガー方程式
It is the beginning of this important quantum mechanics
それはこの重要な量子力学の始まりです
Of course, this year's Nobel lecture confirmed the correctness and magic of quantum mechanics
もちろん、今年のノーベル賞講演は量子力学の正しさと魔法を裏付けた
I'll talk about the magic in a minute
その魔法についてはすぐに話します
is this year's special
今年の特別です
There are many aspects of quantum mechanics that are still incomprehensible
量子力学にはまだ理解できない部分がたくさんあります
But like Einstein said throwing dice
でもアインシュタインがサイコロを振って言ったように
This problem is also confirmed
この問題も確認されています
This year, of course, the Nobel lecture was given to something related to this
今年のノーベル賞講演ももちろんこれに関連した内容で行われました。
Then with this dilemma, of course we add Einstein
このジレンマに、もちろんアインシュタインを加えます。
general relativity more than a hundred years ago
100年以上前の一般相対性理論
Plus Newton's Mechanics
プラスニュートン力学
We use Sensory to have all the basic theoretical equations in physics
物理学のすべての基本的な理論方程式を得るために感覚を使用します
Most of the phenomena you just use the theory of these equations
ほとんどの現象はこれらの方程式の理論を使用するだけです
You should be able to gain insight into almost any phenomenon
ほぼすべての現象について洞察を得ることができるはずです
Or you can predict all phenomena
あるいはすべての現象を予測することもできる
The answer is on the other hand
答えは一方で
Also because we've seen a lot of basic examples
また、基本的な例をたくさん見てきたため、
we know all atoms
私たちはすべての原子を知っています
what we know about atoms and more
原子などについて私たちが知っていること
The universe is formed from these basic examples
宇宙はこれらの基本的な例から形成されます
Then of course why there is this basic example
それでは、なぜこのような基本的な例があるのか​​というと、
that's another mystery
それはまた謎だ
But at least we know these basic examples
しかし、少なくとも私たちはこれらの基本的な例を知っています
can do all kinds of understanding
あらゆる種類の理解ができる
So we have the basic ingredients
基本的な材料は揃っています
Plus all table chemistry biomaterials
さらにすべてのテーブル化学バイオマテリアル
any scientific application
あらゆる科学的応用
Seems like we've all figured it out
どうやらみんな分かったようだ
So this is what many people say
それで、多くの人がこう言います
talk about most of the problems
ほとんどの問題について話す
we all have it
私たちは皆それを持っています
should have the answer
答えがあるはずです
so many people think
とても多くの人が考えています
As long as we understand the table from each state
各州の表を理解する限り
individual atoms
個々の原子
we can understand all
私たちはすべてを理解することができます
Of course this is reductionism
もちろんこれは還元主義です
It is an important direction of science in various disciplines
それはさまざまな分野における科学の重要な方向性です
To put it simply, you only need to start from the basic physical structure
簡単に言えば、基本的な物理構造から始めればよいだけです
Come learn about the many universities that have succeeded in physics
物理学で成功を収めた多くの大学について学びましょう
Now start from some of the most basic equation theory theories
それでは、最も基本的な方程式理論のいくつかから始めましょう
you can push all kinds of conclusions
あらゆる種類の結論を押し出すことができます
as many scientists believe
多くの科学者が信じているように
If we knew every gene
すべての遺伝子を知っていたら
we can understand all life phenomena
私たちはあらゆる生命現象を理解できる
Of course, now I know that maybe this thought is a bit too naive
もちろん、今ではこの考えは少し単純すぎるかもしれないとわかっています
And if you use it like this, there is no important problem to solve
このように使用すれば、解決すべき重要な問題はありません
So I remember around the twenty-first century
それで私は21世紀頃のことを覚えています
At the end of the twentieth century some theories were that
20世紀末には次のような理論があった。
Isn't science already... important science is over
科学はもう終わりではないですか...重要な科学は終わりました
should know
知っておくべき
Of course we now know that this is...
もちろん、これが...
still far
まだ遠い
The science we really want to understand is much harder than this
私たちが本当に理解したい科学は、これよりもはるかに難しいです
But here's at least one interesting question
しかし、ここに少なくとも 1 つの興味深い質問があります
it's a philosophical question
それは哲学的な質問です
That is, do we use it like this
つまり、このように使うのでしょうか？
we can understand all the problems
私たちはすべての問題を理解できます
But now we know this
しかし今、私たちはこれを知っています
what i want to say today is
今日私が言いたいことは
We explored from another direction
別の方向から探検してみました
It is these certain phenomena that are possible
可能性があるのはこれらの特定の現象です
But the most important question we unearth
しかし、私たちが明らかにした最も重要な疑問は、
These in each of these complex
これらの複合体のそれぞれにある
The forces between the components of these systems when
これらのシステムのコンポーネント間の力は、
will produce new phenomena
新しい現象を生み出すでしょう
The phenomenon of your merging is that you did not expect it at all
あなたの融合という現象は、あなたが全く予期していなかったものです
is that you understand each element
それぞれの要素を理解しているということです
You don't understand new phenomena either, do you?
新しい現象も分からないですよね？
you have no way of predicting
あなたには予測する方法がありません
predicted
予測された
That's what we're going to talk about today
今日はそれについて話します
A few two examples to explain this
これを説明するための 2 つの例
Then one of the comparisons is very simple
比較の 1 つは非常に簡単です
Of course, if you know carbon
もちろんカーボンのことを知っていれば
you know two carbons
炭素が2つあることを知っていますか
three
三つ
You add in type should understand a lot of carbon
タイプを追加すると、炭素の量が多くなることがわかります
Of course, let me give you an example here
もちろん、ここで例を挙げましょう
carbon can be turned into diamond
炭素はダイヤモンドに変えることができる
It's a very good ghetto. It's hard.
とても良いゲットーだ、大変だ。
But it can also turn into carbon, which is fragile
しかし、壊れやすい炭素になることもあります。
not a very good conductor of electricity
あまり良い電気伝導体ではない
not very good extremist either
あまり良い過激派でもない
it can also become graphite creek
グラファイトクリークにもなる
it is a good conductor of electricity
それは電気の良導体です
Then you can also become carbon nanotubes
そうすればあなたもカーボンナノチューブになれます
It is both a conductor and an insulator
導体でもあり絶縁体でもある
see how you turn it
どのように回すか見てください
you are turning in the wrong direction
あなたは間違った方向を向いています
it becomes a conductor
それは指揮者になります
Can become extinct
過激派になる可能性がある
Then your two layers of graphite creek
それからグラファイトクリークの2層
Can become an insulator, conductor, or superconductor
絶縁体、導体、超電導体になれる
That's the latest research
それが最新の研究です
then found out
それからわか​​った
you put these two
この2つを置きます
This is a very important contribution of our Vice President Zhou here
これは周副社長の非常に重要な貢献です。
is when you want to put these two together
この 2 つを組み合わせたいときは
turned a little
少し向きを変えた
You will find that there is a completely different phenomenon
全く異なる現象が起きていることがわかります
Everything is not what you imagined, carbon
何もかも想像と違うよ、カーボン
Nothing to do with what I said before
前に言った事とは関係ないよ
then this is interesting
それならこれは面白いですね
just something simple
ただ何か単純なこと
But when there are many things
でも、いろいろあると
put together, many new phenomena appear
まとめると、多くの新しい現象が現れます
It's just the easiest
それが一番簡単です
but here we still
しかし、ここで私たちはまだ
We can probably still understand
私たちはまだ理解できるかもしれない
like this why
どうしてこんなふうに
because we have basic company
私たちには基本的な会社があるので
But here we find
しかし、ここで私たちは見つけます
We're pretty much the latest in the field
私たちはこの分野ではほぼ最新です
There are still many questions we don't know yet
まだまだ分からない疑問がたくさんあります
what the hell is going on
一体何が起こっているのか
OK
OK
That's not what we imagined at first
それは私たちが最初に想像していたものではありませんでした
what about here
ここはどうですか
I want to follow a standard
基準に従いたい
emerging behavior
新たな行動
This is almost everyone
これはほぼ全員です
This is from youtube
これはyoutubeからです
There are probably hundreds of thousands of these birds here
おそらくここには何十万羽もの鳥がいるでしょう
it's here
ここにあります
This is called this, what is it called starling
これをこれといいます、ムクドリといいますか
The stardings fly here
スターディングがここに飛んでくる
then you can watch its movement
そうすれば、その動きを観察できます
very interesting
とても興味深い
When they act very
彼らが非常に行動するとき、
compromise together
一緒に妥協する
they are moving together
彼らは一緒に動いています
I stop this sound
この音を止めます
The voice behind is incredible
後ろの声がすごい
This was taken at an airport
これは空港で撮ったものです
it is very amazing
とても素晴らしいです
hundreds of thousands of times
何十万回も
But the direction of their fascination seems to be one
でも彼らの魅力の方向性は一つのようです
So some people are asking how this came about
それで、どうしてこんなことになったのかを尋ねる人もいます
He obviously doesn't have a leader
彼には明らかにリーダーがいない
we little birds are leaderless
私たち小鳥にはリーダーがいない
didn't he have a bird take the lead and say
鳥に率先して言わせたんじゃなかったっけ？
I should put left, right, up, down
左、右、上、下に置く必要があります
he has no leader at all
彼にはリーダーがまったくいない
But his behavior is very clear
しかし、彼の行動は非常に明らかです
they are one in motion
彼らは動いている
How to achieve such a fast one-piece movement
一体どうやってこのような素早い動きを実現するのか
This flock of birds is a famous example, along with the flock of fish
この鳥の群れは魚の群れと並んで有名な例です。
It is emerging collective behavior
集団行動が現れつつある
is the interaction between the elements
要素間の相互作用です
form those special forms
それらの特別なフォームを形成する
is not a property of the original element
元の要素のプロパティではありません
These are, of course, the so-called definitions
もちろん、これらはいわゆる定義です
New New King is every element of your original
New New King はあなたのオリジナルのあらゆる要素です
Individually have some special properties
個別にいくつかの特別な特性を持っています
but when added together
しかし、合計すると
Those properties may have been lost in individual properties
これらのプロパティは個々のプロパティで失われている可能性があります
it has new properties appearing
新しいプロパティが表示されます
So wait a minute, these two examples I'm going to give
ちょっと待ってください、これから挙げる 2 つの例は
The example I'm going to talk about today
今日お話しする例は
it has something to do with this
それはこれと関係があります
Then the two examples I gave
次に、私が挙げた 2 つの例
Today is one that I have been working on for many years
今日は私が長年取り組んできたものです
quantum physics of course
もちろん量子物理学
The simplest one is, of course, what I want to talk about is the phenomenon of superconductivity.
一番単純なのは、言うまでもなく、私が話したいのは超伝導現象です。
This material superconductivity phenomenon is from top to bottom
この物質の超電導現象は上から下へ
The so-called top-down means that I already know the basic theory
いわゆるトップダウンとは、基本的な理論はすでに知っているということです
Starting from these theoretical models to explain the phenomenon of Yongerjing
これらの理論モデルから出発して永京現象を説明する
hope is
希望は
But of course we can find that many are beyond our original imagination
しかし、もちろん、多くは私たちの当初の想像を超えていることがわかります
Another example of exactly the opposite is classical physics
まったく逆のもう一つの例は古典物理学です
Collective phenomenon of cranial nerves
脳神経の集合現象
That's what I've studied for many years
それが私が長年研究してきたことです
In fact, in recent years
実は近年、
especially after retirement
特に退職後は
More time to study is
勉強する時間が増えるのは、
Collective phenomena of the cranial nerves
脳神経の集合現象
This is bottom up
これはボトムアップです
So the two examples are the exact opposite
したがって、2 つの例はまったく逆です
is that it is generalized from the experimental data
それは実験データから一般化されたものであるということです
Deriving new physics to advance complete theories
完全な理論を前進させるための新しい物理学を導き出す
This is of course far from a complete theory.
もちろん、これは完全な理論には程遠いです。
Just start looking for data now
今すぐデータを探し始めましょう
new laws of physics
新しい物理法則
Such an approach is, of course, two extreme examples.
もちろん、このようなアプローチは 2 つの極端な例です。
one is
一つは
And these two examples are actually these two
そして、これら 2 つの例は実際には次の 2 つです
In this Emergency Behavior
今回の緊急行動では
A real example of two extremes
2 つの極端な例
very extreme example
非常に極端な例
One is that we know very little
1つは、私たちが知っていることがほとんどないということです
one is that we know a lot
1つは、私たちは多くのことを知っているということです
But we still have a lot of new emergency phenomena
しかし、まだ新しい緊急現象がたくさんあります
is what we're totally groping for
それは私たちが完全に模索しているものです
unexpected
予想外の
So what about these two examples
それでは、これら 2 つの例はどうでしょうか
The two I specifically chose are the ones that happen to be Almost Extreme
私が特に選んだ 2 つは、偶然にもほぼ極端なものです
Counter Exam
反証試験
I am a quantity
私は量です
one is bitter
一つは苦い
The first place that talked about why the instructor chose the instructor at the time can understand
当時の講師がなぜその講師を選んだのかがわかる一着
This is really an emerging phenomenon
これは本当に新たな現象です
The first example was conducted in 1911, you may have heard
最初の例は 1911 年に実施されました。聞いたことがあるかもしれません。
This is the most famous one, which is in the museum
これは博物館にある最も有名なものです
This Gentlemen Hike, Camelin Onnes at Lydon University
この紳士のハイキング、ライドン大学のキャメルン・オンズ
Last time I visited they had a Museum
前回訪れたときは博物館がありました
There he has this picture, the resistance of his two arches
そこに彼はこの写真を持っています、彼の2つのアーチの抵抗
It is found that at about 4.2 degrees, its resistance becomes very small
約4.2度で抵抗が非常に小さくなることがわかります。
about 10's of -50's ohms, he jumped 5 orders of magnitude to get here
-50オームの約10桁、彼はここに到達するために5桁ジャンプしました
almost like
ほぼ同じような
This question is of course interesting
この質問はもちろん興味深いです
The question is is it really 0 or almost 0
問題は、それが本当に 0 なのか、それともほぼ 0 なのかということです
It's certainly an interesting question
確かに興味深い質問ですね
Because 0 is not a simple number
0は単純な数ではないので
0 is not 0.001
0は0.001ではありません
nor 0.001
0.001でもない
It's just 0 without any decimal point
小数点のないただの0です
This is of course a very special number
もちろん、これは非常に特別な番号です
Is it because the experiment is not done well?
実験がうまくできていないからでしょうか？
So of course there was a lot of debate when it came out
もちろん、発売当時は多くの議論がありました
Of course it took promise
もちろん約束が必要だった
not for this reason
このためではありません
just saw super old
超古いのを見たばかりです
It uses the Noble watch because it does low-temperature experiments
低温実験を行うためノーブルウォッチを使用しています
It lowers the temperature to
温度を下げます
So he was breaking the Guinness Records
つまり彼はギネス記録を破っていたのです
lowest temperature
最低気温
it reaches the minimum
それは最小限に達します
This is an absolute temperature of 4.2 degrees
これは絶対温度4.2度です
is now minus 269 degrees
現在マイナス269度です
We set negative 269 degrees
マイナス269度を設定します
OK 269 degrees
OK 269度
terribly cold
ひどく寒い
It can achieve this lowest temperature and it finds strange phenomena
この最低温度を達成することができ、奇妙な現象を発見します
so it bumps from that
それでそれはそこからぶつかる
Tell it that it's not because of the discovery of superconductors
超電導体の発見のせいではないと伝えてください
HV discovers superconductor has no promise yet
HVは超電導体にはまだ約束がないことを発見
In addition to the high-temperature superconductors that I will talk about later
後述する高温超伝導体に加えて
In fact, no one talks about it because of this.
実際、このため誰もそれについて話していません。
But let's think about it around that time
でもその時に考えてみましょう
Is it true spirit or almost spirit
それは本当の精神ですか、それともほとんど精神ですか
Of course, let's first understand the mechanism of resistance
もちろん、まずは抵抗のメカニズムを理解しましょう
Let me talk about blocking mechanism and this review
ブロックメカニズムとこのレビューについて話しましょう
i think everyone knows
誰もが知っていると思います
You have an electric box
電気ボックスをお持ちですか
It will be a little shocking when it is in motion
動いているとちょっと衝撃的です
Electricity crash
電気事故
like atomic boxes and so on or other electrons bumping around
原子箱など、あるいは他の電子がぶつかり合うようなもの
Of course, it's quite complicated for you to go from here to here.
もちろん、ここからここに行くのは非常に複雑です。
you're going to hit a lot of places
たくさんの場所に行くことになるでしょう
so you have resistance
だから抵抗があるんだね
will create resistance
抵抗を生むだろう
Sometimes it hits you and it hits back and back and back
時々、それはあなたに当たる、それはあなたに当たる、それはあなたに当たる、それはあなたに当たる、それはあなたに当たる
So this is when you are exercising
これは運動しているときです
it doesn't go in a straight line
それは一直線に進まない
so simple
とても簡単
So there is resistance
だから抵抗があるんだよ
everyone understands this
誰もがこれを理解しています
this is
これは
Just like liquids have resistance when they flow
液体が流れるときに抵抗があるのと同じように、
The problem with this is, but this graph
問題は、このグラフです。
But when everyone makes this picture
でもみんなでこの絵を作ると
everyone is thinking
みんなが考えている
The question of whether it is a spirit or not just now becomes very interesting.
今、それが霊であるかどうかという問題が非常に興味深いものになっています。
Why? These two pictures
なぜでしょうか?この 2 つの写真は
This picture I put together two pictures
この写真は2枚の写真を組み合わせたものです
A green wire is a resistor
緑色の線は抵抗です
it slows down with the temperature
温度とともに遅くなります
When it reaches a temperature we call the temperature of the spirit world
ある温度になると霊界の温度と呼ばれます
it becomes spirit, descends to spirit
それは霊になる、霊に降りる
But the other line draws the heat capacity
しかし、もう一方の線は熱容量を示します
What is heat capacity?
熱容量とは何ですか?
That is to say, if you add a nine-hour heat
つまり、9時間加熱すると、
how many degrees will it heat up
何度まで熱くなりますか
Every material is different
それぞれ素材が違います
Its temperature rises and rises like water
その温度は水のようにどんどん上がっていきます
Everyone thinks to add a lot of heat and it will rise by one degree
熱をたくさん加えれば1度上がるだろうと誰もが思う
OK, some of them are easy to upgrade
OK、それらの中には簡単にアップグレードできるものもあります
That temperature rise
その温度上昇
change with temperature
温度によって変化する
How much hot dust can be absorbed by its heat capacity
熱容量によってどのくらいの高温塵を吸収できるか
are different
異なっています
Then this picture, why show this picture?
では、この写真、なぜこの写真を見せるのでしょうか？
Don't explain it in this picture, why?
この写真では説明しないでください、なぜですか？
But this graph has a very special idea
しかし、このグラフには非常に特別な考え方があります
So at this point it suddenly gets bigger and smaller
この時点で、急に大きくなったり小さくなったりします
I'll tell you this right away
これをすぐに伝えます
Above and below this temperature
この温度以上でも以下でも
The material will change
素材が変わります
This material is not the original material
この素材はオリジナルの素材ではありません
below this temperature
この温度以下では
Because it suddenly has a completely different
突然全く違うものになるから
Variations with temperature
温度による変化
so you think
だからあなたはそう思います
This is actually
これは実際には
If you know that water turns into steam
水が水蒸気になることを知っていれば
This also has a similar behavior
これも同様の動作をします
when a similar phenomenon
同様の現象があったとき
know it's a phase change
それは相変化だということを知ってください
phase transition
相転移
But this temperature is called transboundary temperature
しかし、この温度は越境温度と呼ばれます
These are two crossing points towards the middle
これらは中央に向かう 2 つの交差点です
is a boundary temperature
は境界温度です
The middle makes water change from liquid to gas
真ん中は水を液体から気体に変化させます
is 4100 degrees
4100度です
So everyone knows it's a transboundary temperature
だから誰もがそれが国境を越えた温度であることを知っています
here is a problem
ここに問題があります
Of course the two are not exactly the same
もちろん両者は全く同じではありません
but almost
しかし、ほとんど
So I use this to say
だから私はこれを使ってこう言います
For example, everyone is familiar with
たとえば、誰もが知っている
but here to tell you
しかし、ここでお伝えしたいのは
it is a phase transition
それは相転移です
So this metamorphosis
それでこの変態は
may be real spirit
本物の霊かもしれない
because it has a phase transition
相転移があるから
it's not almost 0
ほぼ0ではない
If there is no phase inversion surface
位相反転面がない場合
It's very likely that you didn't do the experiment well.
実験がうまくできなかった可能性が非常に高いです。
This problem is of course now often when new superconductors are discovered
もちろん、この問題は新しい超伝導体が発見されたときによく発生します。
This question should be fried
この質問はやめるべきです
Did you really see a superconductor or a fake?
本当に超電導体を見たのですか、それとも偽物ですか?
This problem is all
この問題がすべてだ
Of course, there are other experiments
もちろん他にも実験はあります
But this experiment tells you very clearly
しかし、この実験は非常にはっきりと示しています
there is a horizontal
水平があります
there is a Xiangtai
翔台がある
And this Xiangtai has entered a new state
そしてこの翔台は新たな状態に入った
it's high temperature
気温が高いです
arch
アーチ
The situation is completely different from its low temperature situation
低温の状況とは全く違います
is another situation
別の状況です
It changes the whole system
システム全体が変わります
when this changes
これが変わるとき
it suddenly becomes 0
突然0になる
this is of course interesting
これはもちろん面白いです
like i just said 0
先ほど言ったように0
not 0.0000
0.0000ではありません
is 0
0です
That's a Magic Number
それは魔法の数字です
this is
これは
I remember a long time ago I read a book
昔読んだ本を思い出した
Chinese before
以前の中国語
When using zero, don't use zero
ゼロを使​​用する場合はゼロを使用しないでください
Chinese don't have zero
中国人にはゼロはない
In the beginning, the Chinese had both positive and negative
当初、中国人にはポジティブな感情とネガティブな感情の両方があった
jump over zero
ゼロを飛び越える
I don't want to write this zero
このゼロは書きたくない
this zero is one
このゼロは1です
Jiexun is one
ジシュンもその一人
indian mathematician
インドの数学者
raised zero
ゼロを上げました
then this zero
それからこのゼロ
Ten out is very special
テンアウトはとても特別です
In fact, this is of course very related to quantum
実際、これはもちろん量子と非常に関連しています。
Because zero is like zero one two three
ゼロはゼロ 1 2 3 のようなものだから
Precise
正確
not zero zero one
ゼロゼロワンではない
either have
どちらかが持っています
or nothing nothing
あるいは何もない
almost likely to have
ほぼ持っている可能性が高い
ok
Ok
he is very sure
彼はとても確信しています
then here is
それからここにあります
Let this happen as soon as he comes out
彼が出てきたらすぐにこれを起こさせてください
Once confirmed, it is known that this is a quantum phenomenon
一度確認されると、これは量子現象であることがわかります。
You have entered a quantum state
あなたは量子状態に入りました
This is known immediately from a
これは、次のことからすぐにわかります。
state of classical physics
古典物理学の現状
It can be said that it has entered a quantum state.
量子状態に入ったと言える。
up the system
システムをアップする
Then this is of course at a very low temperature
もちろんこれは非常に低い温度です
Very high temperature, is it possible for four temperatures
非常に高温ですが、4 つの温度に対応できますか?
After 46 years of hard work
46年間の努力を経て
Physicists have finally come up with a theory to explain this phenomenon
物理学者たちはついにこの現象を説明する理論を考え出した
Then of course how many arguments went through
それからもちろん、どれだけの議論が通過したか
Find the most famous of these three is
これら 3 つの中で最も有名なものを見つけてください。
Badin, Kupp, Xu Ruifu
バディン、クップ、徐瑞福
Those three came up with a theory in 1957
この3人は1957年にある理論を思いついた
They gave a lecture on this theory in 1972 with a Noble watch
彼らは 1972 年にノーブルの時計を使ってこの理論について講義を行いました。
To explain this phenomenon of manipulation
この操作現象を説明するには
Well, this theory is of course for everyone to see.
まあ、この理論はもちろん誰でも見ることができます。
There are so many new concepts that have changed many minds
多くの人の考えを変えた新しい概念がたくさんあります
That also explains the phenomenon of this manipulation very clearly.
これは、この操作の現象を非常に明確に説明するものでもあります。
this is an outstanding job
これは素晴らしい仕事です
When I went to Buwang University to study for a Ph.D.
私が博士課程の勉強のために富王大学に行ったとき、
It's time for graduate school
大学院の時期が来た
In fact, before I went there, I went to the American library
実はそこに行く前にアメリカの図書館に行ったんです
USIS
USIS
There are many interventions in American universities to check in this way
アメリカの大学ではこのようにチェックするための介入が数多く行われている
he was at brown university
彼はブラウン大学にいた
So I originally wanted to find him as a directing professor
それで私はもともと彼を監督教授として見つけたいと思っていました
Leon Cooper
レオン・クーパー
Say what you say
言うことを言ってください
But after I went there I found out
でも、行ってみて気づいたのは、
People told me he doesn't do physics research
彼は物理学の研究をしていないと言われました
He started doing neuroscience at that time
彼はその頃から神経科学を始めた
just do neuroscience
神経科学をやるだけ
I am the same as I am now
私も今と同じです
Probably because people start doing neuroscience research when they get old
おそらく、人は歳をとると神経科学の研究を始めるからでしょう。
this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いです
I can't help if he doesn't do this
彼がそうしないと私は助けられない
Then I had to change to another professor
その後、別の教授に変えなければなりませんでした
but anyway
とにかく
At that time it turned out that shepherd went to brown university
その時、シェパードであることが判明し、ブラウン大学に進学しました
The explanation of this theory is very explanatory
この理論の説明は非常にわかりやすいです
He not only explained the mechanism of superconductivity
超電導の仕組みを説明しただけではなく、
Why is there superconductivity
超伝導はなぜ起こるのか
for what reason
いかなる理由で
Also understand the quantity-mass state of superconductivity
超伝導の量と質量の状態も理解する
Simultaneously address two major issues
2 つの大きな問題に同時に対処する
their explanation is simple
彼らの説明は簡単です
because of superconductivity
超電導のせいで
The first reason is
一つ目の理由は、
The two batteries become a pair
2つのバッテリーがペアになります
called Cooper pair
クーパーペアと呼ばれる
Cooper Coober vs.
クーパー クーバー vs.
That's Mr. Cooper just now
それは今のクーパーさんです
He proves two batteries
彼は電池が2つあることを証明した
when up and down
上がったり下がったりするとき
one he chooses
彼が選ぶもの
Everyone knows that there is an optional battery
オプションのバッテリーがあることは誰もが知っています
he turns left or right
彼は左か右に曲がります
Clockwise transfer or anti-clockwise transfer
時計回り転送または反時計回り転送
he has two choices
彼には2つの選択肢があります
Which one do you want him to choose?
あなたは彼にどれを選んでもらいたいですか？
but he can
しかし彼にはできる
but there are two
でも2つあります
one up and one down
1 つは上、もう 1 つは下
The two of them like to form a couple
彼ら二人はカップルを形成するのが好きです
This pair is paired up and down
このペアは上下でペアになっています
It's called Cooper pair
クーパーペアといいます
It's an incredibly important job
非常に重要な仕事です
This work broke through at once
この作品で一気にブレイクしました
many questions
たくさんの質問
After this job comes out
この仕事が出てから
He said it was due to this reason
彼はそれがこの理由によるものだと言いました
Fried to Taiwan
台湾への揚げ物
all electricity will do
すべての電気で十分です
Of course this problem is troublesome
確かにこの問題は厄介です
have a problem
問題があります
Because both of them are power
どっちもパワーだから
are the same electricity and
同じ電気であり、
We know that two electricity and
私たちは 2 つの電気と
the same is exclusive
同じことが排他的です
The Max Equation I just talked about
先ほど話したマックス方程式
the old man will know
老人なら分かるだろう
you have no reason
あなたには理由がありません
You two are going to be a couple
お二人はカップルになるんですね
it is clearly repulsive
それは明らかに嫌悪感がある
Isn't the farther away the better?
遠ければ遠いほど良くないですか？
So the question is of course
したがって、質問は当然です
Need to find a mechanism immediately
すぐにメカニズムを見つける必要がある
why doesn't it reject
なぜ拒否しないのか
become attractive
魅力的になる
Will the two of them be attracted to each other?
果たして二人は惹かれ合うのでしょうか？
Then they also found the reason
すると彼らもその理由を見つけた
They all found the reason
彼らは皆その理由を見つけた
Of course there is a reason
もちろん理由があります
Their paper can be completed in one go
彼らの論文は一度で完成することができます
The reason is that
その理由は、
Because this is in the material
資料に載っているので
There are also positively charged nuclei
正に帯電した原子核も存在する
The atomic nucleus is positively charged
原子核はプラスに帯電している
electrons are negative
電子はマイナスです
the nucleus vibrates
原子核が振動する
When the nuclei are sometimes too close together
核同士が近すぎる場合がある
It likes negative electrons and likes to go
マイナス電子が好きで、行くのが好きです。
Because there are more positive electricity
プラスの電気が増えるから
The positive electron went
プラス電子が行きました
Another electron also likes to go
別の電子も行きたい
If both charges go it becomes
両方の料金が発生すると、次のようになります
seems attractive
魅力的に見える
But their attraction is through
しかし、彼らの魅力は伝わってきます
the retarder behind it
その後ろのリターダー
caused by the environment
環境によって引き起こされる
this is interesting
これは面白い
is your environment will affect
あなたの環境は影響しますか
take your original repulsive force
本来の反発力を取り戻す
become an attraction
アトラクションになる
more than your original repulsion
本来の反発を超えて
Then this is of course a
それから、これは当然のことですが、
incredible assumption
信じられないような仮定
Of course, this assumption was later proved
もちろん、この仮定は後に証明されました
That's why I didn't get the Nobel Prize until 1972.
それが私が1972年までノーベル賞を受賞できなかった理由です。
Because a lot of time to prove these issues
これらの問題を証明するには多くの時間がかかるため、
Of course it was later proved
もちろんその後証明されました
this is fine
これは大丈夫です
Then this is to make people cry
それならこれは人を泣かせることになる
Then I took this all
それから私はこれをすべて受け取りました
Published a special issue for the last time in 100 years
100年ぶりに特別号を発行
To commemorate this 100 years this
この100周年を記念して
The diagram used in the special issue of 100 years since the discovery of superconductors
超電導発見100年特集で使用した図
this is very clear
これは非常に明らかです
It can be explained roughly by the diagram
ざっくりと図で説明すると
not hurt
傷ついていない
your environment will attack you
あなたの環境はあなたを攻撃します
extra appeal
追加のアピール
change your original
オリジナルを変更する
it's interesting
それは面白い
It turns out that the two should be mutually exclusive
この 2 つは相互に排他的であることが判明しました
Suddenly they no longer reject
突然彼らは拒否しなくなりました
That's certainly an interesting question.
確かに興味深い質問ですね。
that's the same problem
それは同じ問題です
Is that electron the original electron?
その電子は元の電子ですか？
Because logically they want to reject
論理的に彼らは拒否したいからです
In fact, the result of this final theory is OK
実際、この最終理論の結果はOKです
tell everyone now
今すぐみんなに伝えてください
He believed that Shenxiu's electrons no longer had the characteristics of the original electrons.
彼は、Shenxiu の電子はもはや元の電子の特徴を持っていないと信じていました。
Electron has lost its original characteristics
電子は本来の性質を失った
This is the difference of emerging
これが新興の違いです
I'll talk later
後で話します
is that you have a new nature
あなたには新しい性質があるということですか
The original old nature is gone
本来の古い自然は消え去った
This is an interesting example
これは興味深い例です
that this is not enough
これでは十分ではないということ
Just like this will not be without electrons
これと同じように電子がなければ成り立ちません
It's just a pair, then you can still bump
それはただのペアだ、それでもぶつかることができる
There are walls and tables or bumps
壁やテーブル、段差がある
But now I use this as an example
しかし今、これを例として使用します
I always think it's the best
それが一番だといつも思う
I haven't been able to find this on YouTube
YouTube でこれを見つけることができませんでした
to manifest this dance
このダンスを表現するために
I don't know if you have seen the old movies
昔の映画を見たことがあるかどうかは知りませんが、
Our older adults used to watch this kind of
私たちの年配の大人たちはよくこの種のものを見ていました
this one from russia
これはロシアから来た
artist, who painted this large in Vienna before the nineteenth century
19世紀以前にウィーンでこの大きな作品を描いた芸術家
Big Borum Dancing, Waltz
大的Borum Dancing,Waltz
dance the waltz, these men and women are paired up like this, they're dancing
ワルツを踊ってください、この男性と女性はこのようにペアになって踊っています
And then they'll spin around, and then they'll switch partners
そして彼らはぐるぐる回って、そしてパートナーを変えるでしょう
Jump like this, no matter how you dance
どんなに踊ってもこのままジャンプして
they never hit the wall table table and each other
壁のテーブルやテーブル同士にぶつかることはありません
It is very harmonious along with the music, no matter how you dance, it is very beautiful
音楽に合わせてとても調和していて、どのように踊ってもとても美しいです。
Two exchanges, how to jump, very harmonious
二人のやりとり、ジャンプの仕方、とても和気あいあいとしています
Most importantly, why doesn't he bump around
最も重要なのは、なぜ彼はぶつからないのかということです
Because their steps are very coherent, in harmony, in tune
なぜなら彼らのステップは非常に首尾一貫しており、調和し、調和しているからです。
he won't each other
彼はお互いにしないだろう
If there is a person who is faster or slower, he will come out soon
もっと速い人、遅い人がいたらすぐに出てくる
It’s so big, so I thought that if there are those movies that dance this
とても大きいので、これを踊る映画があればと思いました
That's really amazing, everyone has to practice for a long time
本当にすごいですね、みんな長い時間練習しないといけませんね
Don't bump around, jump very
ぶつからないで、よくジャンプしてください
But if you think about it, now I'm drawing
でもよく考えたら今絵を描いてます
One is an electron going up and one is going down
1つは上昇する電子、もう1つは下降する電子です
These two electrons are like this, and they are optimal in the whole material.
この 2 つの電子はこのように、物質全体の中で最適です。
Ten twenty three electrons
10 23 電子
sons of ten or twenty
10歳か20歳の息子たち
Astronomical numbers are doing this
天文学的な数字がこれをやっている
then exchange each other
それからお互い交換して
They are exchanging positive and negative
彼らはポジティブとネガティブを交換しています
Zhi Zhi spin up
志志スピンアップ
Zhixuan down here to exchange back and forth
Zhixuan がここに来て前後に交換します
then all jumping
それからみんなジャンプしてる
But they didn't bump into each other
でも彼らはぶつからなかった
none hit
何もヒットしませんでした
Even if there are tables and chairs, they won't hit each other
テーブルと椅子があってもぶつからない
so no electrons
だから電子がない
This is a quantum state
これは量子状態です
This is an all-seeing quantum state
これはすべてを見渡す量子状態です
What's the meaning
どのような意味です
It's all electrons working together to do the same thing
すべての電子が協力して同じことをしているのです
a fully owned electron
完全に所有された電子
This is an amazing imagination
これは素晴らしい想像力ですね
if you imagine this
これを想像すると
How could such a thing happen in the world
どうしてこんなことが世の中で起こるのか
How do you make electronics so obedient
どうすれば電子機器をそこまで従順にできるのでしょうか
all do the same thing
みんな同じことをする
And do it very well
そしてそれをとてもうまくやります
You have another table and chair
別のテーブルと椅子があります
Like the thing that produces resistance just mentioned
先ほどの抵抗を生むもののように
has no effect on it
それには何の影響もありません
because it doesn't
そうならないから
it is on a measuring stand
それは測定台の上にあります
if you're going to hit it
打つつもりなら
it's going to knock it into another gauge
別のゲージに落ちてしまうだろう
Can't hit
打てない
That energy is too much
そのエネルギーは多すぎる
The impact of Huotong is impossible to hit
Huotongの衝撃はヒットすることは不可能です
Of course if you add a lot of force
もちろん強い力を加えると
add some extra power
追加のパワーを追加する
you will destroy it
あなたはそれを破壊するでしょう
But you can't do it on the platform
しかし、プラットフォームではそれができません
It is expressed as this scale
このスケールで表されます
Then you usually apply a small voltage and current
次に、通常は小さな電圧と電流を加えます。
it just kept running
それはただ走り続けた
it doesn't
そうではありません
it won't go in
それは入りません
In fact, it has been proved by this experiment
実はこの実験でも証明されています
They have done it with a national laboratory in the US
彼らは米国の国立研究所と協力してそれを行いました
What I did was pass the current through the super tower
私がしたのはスーパータワーに電流を流すことだった
flushed it for probably years
おそらく何年もそれを洗い流しました
That current is always running
その電流は常に流れている
it works
できます
The current starts to take you away from the battery
電流がバッテリーからあなたを奪い始めます
the current keeps running
電流は流れ続ける
it won't stop
止まらないよ
After running for several years
数年間走り続けた結果、
they turn off
彼らはオフになります
because it has no
それは無いので
I think I'm a little slow on this
これについては少し遅いと思います
Oops
おっと
What about the electron?
電子はどうでしょうか？
His other direction is that he doesn't like external magnetic fields
彼のもう一つの方向性は、外部磁場が好きではないということです。
he will cause
彼は引き起こすだろう
Negative forces in different directions
さまざまな方向の負の力
Then he went up
それから彼は上がっていきました
This wisdom spin will be more than the next wisdom spin
この知恵のスピンは次の知恵のスピン以上のものになります
just if you have
あなたが持っているなら
some time to dance
踊る時間
more men than women
女性よりも男性の方が多い
What are some men doing?
一部の男性は何をしているのでしょうか？
will be smashed over there
あそこで潰されるだろう
Ah, this is troublesome
ああ、面倒だ
so they don't like
だから彼らは好きではない
Then when you add a magnetic field
次に磁場を加えると
don't like
好きではない
what about this
これはどうですか
So there is the phenomenon of word service
つまり、ワードサービスという現象が存在します
this is a magnetic field
これは磁場です
This is a superconductor
これは超電導体です
magnetic field
磁場
This magnet will hang
この磁石は引っ掛かります
magnetic fields he doesn't like magnetic fields
磁場 彼は磁場が嫌いです
he gets rid of him
彼は彼を追い出す
You see this is a new phenomenon
これは新しい現象だということが分かりますね
none of us expected
私たちの誰も予想していませんでした
This is very smart
これはとても賢いですね
If he doesn't like him, get rid of him
彼が気に入らないなら、彼を追い出しなさい
Exhaust the magnetism to the outside
磁気を外部に排出
he floated
彼は浮かんだ
Then this one is called Massner
それから、これはマスナーと呼ばれます
Well, this is actually very reasonable and simple
まあ、これは実際には非常に合理的でシンプルです
Now we understand that it is simple
今ではそれが簡単であることが分かりました
it's simple
それは簡単です
Farrati's law
ファッラーティの法則
because you added a magnetic field
磁場を加えたから
he will generate electricity
彼は発電するだろう
Current is in the opposite direction to magnetic field
電流は磁界と逆方向です
everybody knows
誰もが知っている
This is Landrow
ランドローです
in that direction
その方向に
It will shield its magnetic field
磁場を遮蔽します
Of course it's normal here
もちろんここではそれが普通です
Why can't normal iron
なぜ普通にアイロンがかけられないのか
Ordinary metal won't
普通の金属では無理だ
because normal metals are
なぜなら通常の金属は
current will be gone
電流がなくなる
With resistance
抵抗あり
Disappear under current
電流の下で​​消える
But this is superconducting
しかし、これは超電導です
it won't
そうはなりません
So the superconductor will always have a current
したがって、超電導体には常に電流が流れます。
keep it blocked
ブロックしたままにしておく
so it will float with great force
すごい勢いで浮きますので
of course this is
もちろんこれは
just said
今言いました
This is Massiness
これをマッシネスといいます
But if you then increase the magnetic field
しかし、その後磁場を増加させると
it can't get rid of
それを取り除くことはできません
too strong
強すぎる
what about it
それはどうですか
it puts it in
それはそれを入れます
how does it go in
どうやって入るの？
it puts it in like a gold grid
それは金の格子のように配置されます
it confines it to a small place
小さな場所に閉じ込めてしまう
That dark place over here has a magnetic field
ここの暗い場所には磁場がある
There is no magnetic field outside
外には磁場はありません
This is what they calculate
これは彼らが計算したものです
This Apricot of the Landrow speaks for itself
このランドローのアプリコットはそれ自体を物語っています
because it lifts the math
それは数学を引き上げるからです
This is called vortex rolling out
これを渦ローリングアウトといいます
show inside
中を見せる
It has a magnetic field inside
中には磁場があるんです
The outside is shielded
外側はシールドされています
OK
OK
so it was very successful
それで大成功でした
Received the Nobel Prize in 2003
2003年にノーベル賞を受賞
This result is of course the result of the experiment at the beginning.
もちろんこの結果は最初の実験の結果です。
very amazing
非常に素晴らしいです
it will line it up nicely
綺麗に並べてくれますよ
this is us to show this
これを見せるのが私たちです
The one just mentioned was an experiment.
先ほど挙げたのは実験です。
oh
おお
I obviously can't do it here
明らかにここでは無理だ
oops
おっと
I'll stop now
もうやめます
this is a bit troublesome
これはちょっと面倒だ
I was going to show how it lined up
どのように並んでいるのかを見せるつもりだった
but i think i might have to hold it up
でも我慢しなければならないかもしれないと思う
But there may not be enough time now
でも今は時間が足りないかもしれない
let me tell you
言っておくけど
there's something special in here
ここには何か特別なものがあります
What I just said
私が今言ったこと
Talking about this nest
この巣について話す
talk like this
このように話します
What about each of these things?
これらそれぞれについてはどうでしょうか？
Actually you
実はあなた
You see it's neatly arranged
きれいに並べられているのがわかります
But everyone has a fixed unit
でも誰もが固定単位を持っています
all the same size
全部同じサイズ
The black dots are all the same size
黒い点はすべて同じ大きさです
Then this is called a special quantum magnetic flux
したがって、これは特殊量子磁束と呼ばれます
It has a certain unit
一定の単位がある
what about this unit
このユニットはどうですか
Planck Conson
プランク・コンソン
Double the pad box
パッドボックスを2倍にする
Twice the pad box is Couple Pair
パッドボックスの2倍はカップルペアです
Couple Pair is two pad boxes
カップルペアは2つのパッドボックスです
two chia
2つのチア
so two
それで2つ
It is H except these two pad boxes
この2つのパッドボックス以外はHです
It is called a standard Flux mine
標準フラックス鉱山と呼ばれています
it everyone
それはみんな
The black dot I just saw
さっき見た黒い点
this is the point
これがポイントです
Then there is no magnetic field in the middle
すると真ん中には磁場がなくなる
magnetic field in
磁場
get in the middle of it
その真ん中に入る
next to the current
現在の隣に
put this magnetic field
この磁場を置く
The magnetic field in the middle is gone
真ん中の磁場が消えた
only in a small area
狭いエリアだけで
you can't even imagine
あなたには想像すらできない
this natural world is wonderful
この自然界は素晴らしいです
This mat seems to have a brand
このマットにはブランドがあるようです
Actually it doesn't have Brand
実際にはブランドはありません
But it doesn't hurt well, it will find a way by itself
でも、あまり痛くない、自分で方法を見つけてくれる
Shrink this magnetic field to a very small distance
この磁場を非常に小さな距離まで縮小します
it does not affect
影響はありません
So most of the place has no magnetic field
つまり、ほとんどの場所には磁場がありません
It did not affect the steering
ステアリングには影響なかった
steer it's still there
操縦してください、まだそこにあります
will not be affected by it
それには影響されません
only a few places
ほんの数か所だけ
This is the best rounding signal
これが最良の丸めシグナルです
think about it
考えてみてください
it's just incredible
それはただ信じられないほどです
it will find your best solution by itself
最適なソリューションを自動的に見つけます
Let this rounding information exist
この丸め情報を存在させます
that this is very small
これはとても小さいこと
but the thing is it's fun
でも大事なのは楽しいということ
It must have integers likewise
同様に整数でなければなりません
This is a quantity effect
これは量的な効果です
It's not another effect
別の効果ではありません
it must be an integer
整数でなければなりません
not an integer not yet
まだ整数ではありません
you can count
数えることができます
You can count the one just now
今数えてもいいよ
Carrying the Triangular Ginger is fine
三角生姜を持ち歩いても大丈夫です
But it must be an integer
ただし整数である必要があります
but you can ask
しかし、尋ねることはできます
Then why do I want integers
では、なぜ整数が必要なのでしょうか
I can apply a magnetic field from the outside
外部から磁場を印加できる
I added a magnetic field outside
外側に磁場を追加しました
any magnetic field
あらゆる磁場
I don't have to be that
そうである必要はない
The multiple of the magnetic flux just now
今の磁束の倍数
multiples of integers
整数の倍数
I can do it 1⁴ can I
できるよ 1⁴ できるよ
1⁹ more
多1⁹行不行
Then if more than 1⁹
1⁹ を超える場合
In fact, there are two possible solutions
実際、考えられる解決策は 2 つあります
One is that your superconductor produces a clockwise current
1 つは、超伝導体が時計回りの電流を生成することです。
add one-half to one
半分を1に足す
generate a current
電流を発生させる
The current starts to run
電流が流れ始める
add one-half
半分を加える
One-half plus one-half becomes one
2分の1と2分の1を足すと1になります
curious
奇妙
But I can run in reverse
でも逆走はできるよ
becomes minus one-half
マイナス2分の1になる
One-half plus minus one-half becomes zero
2分の1プラスマイナス2分の1がゼロになる
I can also be zero
私はゼロになれる
I have two possibilities
私には2つの可能性があります
one running forward
前を向いて走っている人
a reverse run
逆走
One becomes one and one becomes zero
１は１になり、１はゼロになる
it's okay
それは大丈夫
It suits my condition just now
今の私の状態にぴったりです
It must be an integer multiple
整数倍でなければなりません
That is, if you insist on adding half a magnetic head to measure it in
つまり、測定するために磁気ヘッドの半分を追加することを主張する場合、
it can also
それもできます
It can increase the amount of head
ヘッドの量を増やすことができます
it becomes like this
このようになります
but who is right in the end
でも結局誰が正しいのか
Is it one or two
1つか2つですか
The answer is both and neither
答えは両方であり、どちらでもない
the answer is
答えは
Learn to be a cat
猫になることを学ぶ
That is, everyone scanned the superposition state of the two states
つまり、2つの状態を重ね合わせた状態を全員でスキャンしたのです
is its answer
それが答えです
This is Quantum Mechanics
これが量子力学です
most amazing place
最も素晴らしい場所
This answer is also this year
この答えは今年も
Did you talk about it?
それについて話しましたか？
This is to learn to determine a Rams, whether it is one or zero, alive or dead
これは、ラムズが 1 か 0 か、生きているか死んでいるかを判断することを学ぶことです。
You don't know either, both are possible, and both are falling prices
どちらかは分からない、両方の可能性がある、そして両方の価格が下落している
This is used to make Flox, quantum qubit
これは量子量子ビットである Flox を作るために使用されます
Everyone knows that computers need to use this quantum bit
コンピュータがこの量子ビットを使用する必要があることは誰もが知っています
The qubit, if calculated by Flox, is made like this
量子ビットは、Flox で計算すると次のようになります。
As I said just now, there are superconductors here
さっき言ったように、ここには超伝導体があります
Then you have to pass through inside, the magnetic momentum must pass through, it must be an integer number
次に、内部を通過する必要があり、磁気運動量が通過する必要があり、それは整数でなければなりません
I didn't talk about it just now, so it must be an integer
今それについて話さなかったので、それは整数でなければなりません
In it it can do the Flox qubit
その中で Flox 量子ビットを実行できます
Then if you say, if two qubits are placed next to each other today
次に、今日 2 つの量子ビットが隣り合って配置されているとすると、
I only put a magnetic momentum into it
磁気の勢いを入れただけです
It's one is one on the left and zero on the right, or one on the right and zero on the left
それは、左が 1 で右が 0、または右が 1 で左が 0 の 1 です。
it only has two possibilities, right
可能性は2つだけですよね
It is impossible for both to be one and zero at the same time
両方が同時に 1 と 0 になることは不可能です
Zero and one, because put one in
ゼロと１、１を入れるから
What is the sum of these two? This is this year's
これら 2 つの合計は何ですか? これが今年の
I don't want to appeal
控訴したくない
This is today's entanglement
今日の絡みです
this proof
この証拠
If you put these two
この２つを入れると
These two Q ratios are far apart
これら 2 つの Q 比は大きく離れています
it's still the same
それはまだ同じです
If you measure to one
1まで測ると
The other side must be zero
反対側はゼロでなければなりません
because zero is one
ゼロは1だから
this is very simple
これはとても簡単です
But this is beyond
しかし、これは超えています
Of course, today's quantum computers
もちろん、今の量子コンピューターも
Mainly use super to body
主にスーパーからボディに使用します。
I won't talk about this anymore
これについてはもう話さない
But this PCS theory
しかし、このPCS理論は
is a giant quantum effect
巨大な量子効果です
However, some of the original properties are no longer displayed
ただし、元のプロパティの一部は表示されなくなります。
only group sex
グループセックスのみ
So what I said just now is the behavior of groups
つまり、私が今言ったのは集団の行動です
Neither one or two electronic acts
1 つまたは 2 つの電子的行為ではない
All electrons do these things
すべての電子はこれらのことを行います
Do together
一緒にやろう
that's a strange thing
それは奇妙なことだ
but it is very beautiful
でもとても美しいです
sexual behavior
性的行為
but in it
しかしその中で
Of course there are bigger problems
もちろんもっと大きな問題もあります
is it possible for you to say
言えるでしょうか？
There is a Coopers Pass formed
クーパーズパスが形成されています
have no homology
相同性がない
it's too strong
強過ぎです
Just now I said that I am in a team, so I have no electrons
さっきチームだから電子がなくなるって言った
Can't I form a team first without having the same article?
同じ記事を持たないとまずチームを組めないのでしょうか？
As I said earlier, if the room is large, many people will dance
先ほども言いましたが、部屋が広ければたくさんの人が踊ります。
The people over here have already started to dance, but the people over there haven't danced yet
こっちの人たちはもう踊り始めているけど、あそこの人たちはまだ踊っていない
Then there is no same article
それでは同じ記事はありません
Some people dance here at different paces
ここでさまざまなペースで踊る人もいます
Someone is different here, different on both sides
ここでは誰かが違う、両側でも違う
That has CooperPet , but no conformity
CooperPet はありますが、均一性はありません
Then there is no way to become a non-electric group.
そうなると非電化グループになるわけがない。
It's not over-falling, then this phenomenon has never been seen before.
落ちすぎではないということは、この現象はこれまでに見られなかったものです。
But in this 1987
しかしこの1987年には
These two Gentlemen in October
10月のこの二人の紳士
In September, there was PayFer
9月にはPayFerが登場しました
It's going to be a very exciting start to November with a new super-down
新しいスーパーダウンで11月はとてもエキサイティングなスタートになりそうだ
After that, Wu Maokun and I found YBCO
その後、ウー・マオクンと私はYBCOを見つけました。
They were the first to look for it, and they won the Nobel Prize in the second year
彼らはそれを最初に探し、2年目にノーベル賞を受賞した
ok it's very early
わかりました、とても早いです
As early as the second year, the material was brought out to talk about it.
2年目になると早くも、次のことについて話すために資料が持ち出されました。
This is the high-level conductor
こちらは高級指揮者です
At that time, of course, there was another important
もちろんその時、もう一つ重要なことがありました
I also went to participate
私も参加しに行きました
I don't know if Mei Yini went there at that time
メイ・イニがその時そこに行ったかどうかは分かりません
At the March Meeting in New York in 1987
1987年、ニューヨークでの3月集会にて
I will go to participate
参加しに行きます
it was 12 o'clock in the evening
夕方12時でした
it's 12 o'clock at night
夜の12時です
crazy for physicists
物理学者には夢中
in the squeeze
圧迫の中で
There is still a meeting at 12 o'clock in the evening
夜の12時にまだ会議があります
It's been a day
一日が経ちました
I still have to go to the crowded hall to give a speech tonight.
私は今夜​​スピーチをするためにまだ混雑したホールに行かなければなりません。
About Gawain
ガウェインについて
This is WooStar
ウースターです
WooStar is chasing hot singers in the past
WooStarが過去の人気歌手を追っている
star party
スターパーティー
At that time we also did
あの時、私たちもそうしました
Then why am I talking about this?
では、なぜ私はこのことについて話しているのでしょうか？
This is the Gawain conductor
こちらはガウェインの指揮者です
there is a special phenomenon
特別な現象があります
It's supposed to be a special material
特殊な素材なのだろう
time it should be a strong force
強い力になるはずの時
it was supposed to be a conductor
指揮者だったはずだ
Turns out it's an insulator
絶縁体であることが分かりました
Then this picture is a
そうすると、この写真は、
In fact, this picture is too complicated
実はこの絵は複雑すぎる
I won't drop you either
私もあなたを捨てません
but i just want to tell you
でも、ただあなたに言いたいのです
This picture is from a review in 2003
この写真は2003年のレビューのものです
Talk about the picture at that time
当時の写真について語る
At that time they thought that high temperature superconductivity should look like this
当時、彼らは高温超伝導は次のようにあるべきだと考えていました。
but now this half
でも今はこの半分
They only showed half of it, it's too complicated
半分しか見せてなかった、もう複雑すぎる
By 2017, this phase diagram has become much more complicated than this
2017 年までに、この状態図はこれよりもはるかに複雑になりました。
High-temperature superconductivity is always a very complicated phenomenon
高温超伝導は常に非常に複雑な現象です
keeps appearing
現れ続ける
so far there are
これまでのところあります
But the most interesting is the question
しかし、最も興味深いのはその質問です
in this state
この状態で
It seems to have cried, but it is not superconducting
泣いたようですが超電導ではありません
superconducting below this not superconducting above this
これより下は超電導 これより上は超電導ではない
Non-superconducting states do exist
非超電導状態は存在する
I just cried
ただ泣いてしまいました
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
it already has a pair
すでにペアがあります
Then here I just show some measurement results
それでは、ここでいくつかの測定結果を示します
What about their materials?
彼らの材料はどうなっているのでしょうか？
It uses STM
STMを使用しています
STM is a needle tip of my electric current
STMは私の電流の針先です
Like a tip, when I pass a voltage, there will be a current
チップのように、電圧を流すと電流が流れます。
The change in current follows the change in voltage
電流の変化は電圧の変化に続きます
You can see how the electrons on this surface
この表面上の電子の様子がわかります。
how different electronic states
電子状態がどれほど違うのか
like here
ここのような
it goes from here to here
ここからここへ行きます
its electronic state is changing
電子状態が変化している
With voltage
電圧あり
So the current is changing
それで流れは変わっていく
What about this state?
この状態はどうでしょうか？
it shows
それが示している
you have two electrons here
ここには電子が2つあります
Positron
陽電子
it has flaws
それには欠陥があります
This this Calsium
これ、このカルシウム
cover is two
カバーは2枚です
Usually it sends two electrons
通常、2つの電子を送ります
but if you are defective
しかし、あなたに欠陥がある場合
it becomes two less
2つ減ります
put two electrons
電子を2つ置く
Just two positive boxes
たった2つのポジティブボックス
There are two positive boxes near this
この近くにポジティブボックスが2つあります
Two positive boxes become
プラスボックスが2個になります
look like this
このように見える
so it this is
それで、これは
What about the experiment?
実験はどうですか？
is showing
示しています
I just put two electric boxes in it
電気ボックスを2つ入れただけです
you will form
あなたが形成します
It seems that a very strange shape is at the entrance of the building
建物の入り口にとても奇妙な形があるようです
Then if you put two pairs
次に、2つのペアを置くと
it will form more complex phenomena
より複雑な現象を形成するでしょう
Its two pairs will layer horizontally into one large
2 つのペアが水平に重ねられて 1 つの大きなものになります
what if i have 12 pairs today
今日12足持っていたらどうなるでしょうか
put it all together
全部まとめて
what have you become
あなたは何になりましたか
if i have 10
10個あれば
ten times right?
10回ですよね？
ten targets
十的
20 squares right?
20マスですよね？
but you will suffer
しかしあなたは苦しむでしょう
but no homology
しかし相同性はない
it's already bitter
もう苦いです
This is the result of the experiment
これが実験の結果です
why show this
なぜこれを見せるのか
is when you put 10 to 20 squares
10～20マスを置いたとき
you realize
あなたは気づいています
Wow
おお
it's arranged in a special shape
特殊な形状に配置されています
It's inside the building
建物の中です
with these bitter pairs
この苦いペアと
but it doesn't necessarily have the same
しかし、必ずしも同じであるとは限りません
There is zero electricity
電気がゼロです
that's a new phenomenon
それは新しい現象です
It turns out that the BCS theory doesn't fit well again.
BCS 理論がまたもや適合しないことが判明しました。
totally different story
全く別の話
What about this story?
この話はどうでしょうか？
important modern research
重要な現代研究
then this is to tell you
それならこれはあなたに言いたいことです
It's more complicated than we thought
私たちが思っていたよりも複雑です
real emerging behavior
実際の新たな行動
more
もっと
I just talked a little bit about it
それについて少しだけ話しました
That high-security has been developed for 36 years and has been used continuously
36年間開発され、使い続けられているその高いセキュリティ
the most important reason
最も重要な理由
Its electronic construction is very strong
その電子構造は非常に強力です
with a lot of new emerging behavior
多くの新たな動作を伴う
As I just said, there are new ones every year
先ほども言いましたが、毎年新しいものが登場します
still not finished
まだ終わっていない
You haven't finished frying this material, there are too many new things
この材料はまだ揚げ終わっていません、新しいものが多すぎます
Then we don't find out what to do
それでは何をすればいいのか分からない
The above theories are all top-down
上記の理論はすべてトップダウンです
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
we have basic couple pair
基本的なカップルペアがあります
Just this idea superconducting
このアイデアだけで超電導
Then I go like this
それから私はこのように行きます
try to apply it to more complex phenomena
より複雑な現象に適用してみてください
But some are successful and some are not
しかし、成功するものもあれば、失敗するものもあります
OK
OK
The other is to say
もう一つは、こう言うことです
it's us
それは私たちです
That is, we work from the bottom up
つまり、ボトムアップで作業します
just look at the data
データを見てください
the most famous example
最も有名な例
I now give this example
今この例を挙げます
Take the example of the flock of birds just now
先ほどの鳥の群れを例に挙げてみましょう
how do physicists understand it
物理学者はそれをどのように理解していますか
do the dumbest way
最も愚かな方法をする
take pictures
写真を撮る
take a quick photo
簡単に写真を撮ります
when every bird is flying
すべての鳥が飛んでいるとき
what is its direction
その方向性は何ですか
it is the direction of velocity
それは速度の方向です
OK
OK
this is speed
これがスピードだ
then its direction
それからその方向
Take the image volume of this speed and put it
この速度の画像ボリュームを取得して配置します
Find out, and then ask whether these two directions are related
これら 2 つの方向に関連性があるかどうかを調べて尋ねてください。
just do this
ただこれをしてください
Because of this matter, the data is analyzed, and then a model is fit
このため、データが分析され、モデルが適合されます。
The model is like this, only these two quantities
これは、これら 2 つの項だけを含むモデルです
For example, for each bird, there are about eight birds beside it
たとえば、それぞれの鳥の隣に約 8 羽の鳥がいます。
This NC is good, let's say eight are good
このNCは良いです、8つが良いとしましょう
Ask about the relationship between the eight birds next to it and it
隣の8羽の鳥とそれとの関係を尋ねる
Then you do it, just write it as a simple model
後はそれを実行し、単純なモデルとして記述するだけです
They did it and it turned out to be
彼らはそれをやった、そして結果としてこうなった
this professor did
この教授はやった
Let’s talk about that APS
APS について話しましょう
This work is very beautiful, after finishing
この作品は完成後とても美しいです
This is too simple, more simple idea
これは単純すぎる、もっと単純なアイデア
I just go to fit
ただフィットしに行くだけです
Turns out the bird-to-bird relatedness is a borderline
鳥と鳥の関連性は境界線であることが判明
Just now I have talked about what is called the critical state, in the middle of two phases
今、私は 2 つのフェーズの真ん中にある、いわゆる臨界状態について話しました。
they're on edge
彼らは危機に瀕している
This is of course, why he is on edge, no one knows
もちろんこれが彼がイライラしている理由だ、誰も知らない
but he's on edge
でも彼は緊張している
And it's a very beautiful critical state
そしてそれはとても美しい臨界状態です
this is a very interesting
これはとても興味深いですね
But the state of this part is of course the most important reason, we can explain it with this iron pool
しかし、もちろんこの部分の状態が最も重要な理由であり、この鉄プールで説明できます。
Everyone knows that iron pools are magnetic at low temperatures
鉄プールは低温では磁性を示すことは誰もが知っています
But at high temperature, if you raise the iron pool to high temperature, there will be no magnetism
しかし高温では、鉄プールを高温にすると磁性はなくなります。
Each magnetic transition up or down
それぞれの磁気転移が上または下に
like we say one or minus one
私たちが言う「ワンワン」や「マイナスワン」のように
You can down and up be one plus one or minus one
ダウンとアップは 1 プラス 1 またはマイナス 1 になります。
But if you are in very high temperature
ただし、非常に高温になっている場合は、
Each magnetic spin can be up or down at will
各磁気スピンは自由に上下することができます
so it adds up to zero
だから合計するとゼロになる
when you're cold
寒いとき
Each magnetic spin tries to be the same as the one next to it
それぞれの磁気スピンは隣の磁気スピンと同じになろうとします
These two have the same lower energy
これら2つは同じより低いエネルギーを持っています
These two are different, the energy is higher
この二つは違う、エネルギーが高い
it doesn't like
それは好きではありません
so it likes to be with it
だからそれと一緒にいるのが好きです
Then this is Ice in model
それからこれはモデルのアイスです
This is a very simple model
これは非常にシンプルなモデルです
called the Ice in magnetic spin model
Ice in 磁気スピンモデルと呼ばれる
So everyone in the literature has probably learned this
したがって、文学者なら誰もがおそらくこれを学んだでしょう
up or down
上か下
Then this model it is very simple
それからこのモデルは非常にシンプルです
There's a weird thing about this model
このモデルには奇妙な点があります
You can imagine black going up and white going down
黒が上昇し、白が下降することを想像できます
Then this is a very messy and disorderly image.
これは非常に乱雑で無秩序な画像です。
But at low temperature
ただし低温では
What about when it's cold?
寒いときはどうでしょうか？
it will be more and more like it will be
ますますそうなるだろう
more and more white
ますます白くなる
There will be fewer and fewer black pictures like this one
このような黒い写真はますます少なくなるでしょう
Of course, there may be more and more black
もちろん黒人も増えるかもしれない
less and less white
ますます白が少なくなる
but it's all possible
でもそれはすべて可能です
But when you are at part temperature
しかし、部分温度にいるときは、
will find a strange phenomenon
奇妙な現象を見つけるでしょう
it's not much white
あまり白くありません
less black
黒が少ない
White, black, not much difference
白、黒、大差ない
but
しかし
it's always big
いつも大きいです
The white one is also big
白いのも大きいですね
The black one is also big
黒も大きいです
There is black in the middle of the white
白の真ん中に黒がある
The black ones look carefully and there are white ones inside
黒いものをよく見ると中に白いものが入っています
become complicated
複雑になる
It's different from the low temperature
低温とは違うよ
Of course it's not the same as high temperature
もちろん高温とは違いますが
Each independent black and white is completely random
それぞれ独立した黒と白は完全にランダムです
Then this phenomenon can be explained
そうするとこの現象は説明できる
And it was Ansack who explained it back then.
当時それを説明してくれたのはアンサックだった。
This is in the middle of order and disorder
ここは秩序と無秩序の真ん中
In this zero-medium state neither is the case
このゼロ中間状態ではどちらも当てはまりません
It's not what I just said
それは私が今言ったことではありません
It is also not ordered in the middle of two
2つの途中で注文することもできません
it's right in the middle right here at this point
この時点でちょうど真ん中あたりです
The disordered direction means zero on average at high temperature
方向の乱れは高温では平均ゼロを意味する
because half up and half down
半分上がって半分下がったから
the odds are the same
確率は同じです
But at low temperatures almost all upward
しかし、低温ではほぼすべて上向きになります
you're not so sure at this temperature
この温度ではよくわかりません
it's up some up
だいぶ上がってきました
so it's not a special
だからそれは特別なことじゃない
right at the boundary of the two faces
ちょうど二つの面の境界線に
it looks like both up and down
上にも下にも見える
but it's not quite
しかしそれは完全ではありません
it's a strange state
奇妙な状態です
Then this strange state is a state of concealing the mirror
するとこの奇妙な状態は鏡を隠した状態です
Then of course it is here
それならもちろんここです
If you look at the correlation distance
相関距離を見てみると
Associated functions Both are associated functions
関連関数 どちらも関連関数です
Usually there is an association distance
通常、結合距離が存在します
There is no association beyond the association distance
関連距離を超える関連はありません
But low temperature and high temperature have a correlation distance
ただし、低温と高温には相関距離があります
But there is no correlation distance at midnight temperature
しかし、深夜の気温では相関距離はありません
The association distance is infinite
アソシエーション距離は無限です
that this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いことです
This first one, this math is of course a bit
この最初のもの、この数学はもちろんちょっとしたものです
If you know that this is in the form of an exponential
これが指数関数の形であることがわかっている場合
Then this is when Tc
それからこれはTcのときです
it is density
それは密度です
ok
Ok
it has no size
サイズがありません
fractal
フラクタル
It behaves completely differently
まったく異なる動作をします
I just said that the flock of birds is in this phenomenon.
鳥の群れがこの現象の中にあると先ほど言いました。
I'll get to this quickly now
今からすぐに取り掛かります
The biggest problem is that there are a lot of
最大の問題は量が多いことだ
special phenomenon
特殊な現象
Just at this Tc time
ちょうどこの時間に
It becomes infinite in many things
いろんな事で無限になる
If an infinite system
無限系なら
not infinite system
無限システムではない
it gets big
大きくなる
Then I will summarize it
それではまとめていきます
just talked too much
ただ話しすぎただけ
Maybe everyone will be the first to have a meal reserve
おそらく誰もが最初に食事の準備をするでしょう
at high temperature it is not
高温ではそうではありません
Infinity at low temperature
低温で無限大
it is
それはです
Ordered and disordered in the middle to an intermediate state in the middle
中間の秩序と無秩序から中間の中間状態へ
This state is a special state
この状態は特殊な状態です
Then this state is an emerging state
そうするとこの州は新興州です
It's not surprising that everyone goes up
全員が上がっても不思議ではない
like we have spin
スピンがあるように
two just two together
二人だけ一緒に
he also likes to go up
彼は登るのも好きです
So not too new emerging station
それほど新しい新興駅ではないので、
It's not unusual to turn around
振り向くのは珍しいことではない
there are many words
たくさんの言葉があります
Of course there are some who don't like to go up
もちろん登りたくない人もいる
he goes up
彼は上がる
but at high temperature
しかし高温では
stand in this position
この位置に立つ
he's weird
彼は変だ
His association training is infinite
彼の協会トレーニングは無限です
he has no distance
彼には距離がない
That is to say, you are in the ratio of one centimeter to two centimeters
つまり、あなたは1センチメートルと2センチメートルの比率にあります
The ratio of one meter to two meters
1メートルと2メートルの比率
100km is the same as 200km
100kmと200kmは同じです
OK
OK
he makes no difference
彼は何の違いもありません
he doesn't care how far you are
彼はあなたがどれだけ離れているかなんて気にしません
his mutual size
彼のお互いのサイズ
all the same size
全部同じサイズ
So this is what I just said
それで、これが私が今言ったことです
Fractal Self-Similarity
フラクタル自己相似性
that question
その質問
let's talk
話しましょう
The question I was going to talk about today
今日話そうと思っていた質問
Pity
残念
to talk about this mind
この心について話すために
so big, and the cerebellum has so many neurons
とても大きくて、小脳には非常に多くのニューロンがある
how do we understand
どうやって理解するのですか
That's all Guoyi's mind is
Guoyi の心はそれだけです
How to understand the brain?
脳を理解するにはどうすればよいでしょうか？
Of course someone made one
もちろん誰かが作った
I'll talk a little bit quickly
少し急いで話します
did an experiment
実験をしました
how to do it
どうやってするの
this is an interesting experiment
これは興味深い実験です
Everyone knows to use VR to play
VR を使ってプレイすることは誰もが知っています
when game play
ゲームプレイ時
But the New York Science of Physicists
しかし、ニューヨークの物理学者の科学
It is used to show the old
古いものを示すために使用されます
This VR video
このVR動画は
make him think he's running outside
彼に外で走っていると思わせる
In fact, the old man is running on this ball
実際、老人はボールの上を走った
But he has a camera on his head
でも頭にはカメラがついてる
Can videotape his brain lights up
彼の脳が活性化する様子をビデオに撮ることができるか
lights up when he sees something
彼が何かを見ると光る
Showed him some illusions
彼にいくつかの幻想を見せた
He has been running and watching
彼は走ったり見たりしていた
Then the brain keeps recording
そして脳は記録し続ける
It's an amazing experiment
すごい実験ですね
beautifully done
美しく完成しました
You didn't expect to do such a beautiful experiment
こんな素晴らしい実験をするとは予想していませんでした
He looks at the brain
彼は脳を見ます
What does it have to do with what he saw?
それは彼が見たものと何の関係があるのでしょうか？
This is
これは
data to be tested
テストするデータ
data we make
私たちが作るデータ
I made it very simple with a professor
教授と一緒にとても簡単に作りました
very cheap
とても安い
Put a small camera on the head of the mouse
マウスの頭に小型カメラを搭載
Called Mini scope
ミニスコープと呼ばれる
So it was Professor Wu Dongchuan who worked at China Medical University
それは中国医科大学で働いていた呉東川教授でした
then give him a
それから彼に与えてください
run inside the barracks
兵舎の中を走る
You see he's selling too
彼も売れているのがわかります
so we can keep track of which cowherds are selling
どの牛飼いが販売しているかを追跡できるようにするため
Which cowherds are selling
どの牛飼いが売っているのか
we have data
データがあります
Just like this is a very delicate matter
ただ、これはとてもデリケートな問題なので、
This is a very famous thing
これはとても有名なことです
This is probably Cadillac
これはおそらくキャデラックです
This is probably a cheap car
これはおそらく安い車です
this is
これは
this result
この結果
the result we made
私たちが作った結果
I don't talk anymore
もう話さない
just to tell you yes
ただあなたにそうだと言うために
What we end up with is almost the same
最終的に得られるものはほぼ同じです
is found
見つかった
in these phenomena
こういった現象の中で
see the experiment
実験を見てください
are in Critical state
重大な状態にあります
are near the critical temperature
臨界温度に近い
That is, the temperature of the experiment is T1
つまり、実験の温度はT1です。
the temperature of the experiment
実験の温度
But we use this to analyze
しかし、これを分析に使用します
Other data we found that it is almost all in the part temperature
他のデータでは、ほぼすべてが部​​品温度にあることがわかりました。
This is very complicated data made with others
これは他人と協力して作成した非常に複雑なデータです
It's the same for others to do very complex data
非常に複雑なデータを扱うのは他の人にとっても同じです
What we do is a very simple debut of the data
私たちが行うのは、データの非常に単純なデビューです。
But the answer is almost exactly the same
でも答えはほぼ同じです
This is a very interesting phenomenon
これはとても興味深い現象です
This phenomenon doesn't make much sense from physics.
この現象は物理学的にはあまり意味がありません。
If the part phenomenon
部品現象の場合
It's not quite Depend on detail
それは完全ではありません詳細に依存します
Many details are not important
多くの詳細は重要ではありません
It only cares about some important parameters of this long distance
この長距離のいくつかの重要なパラメータのみを考慮します
Here we use very debut measurements and very precise measurements
ここでは、非常にデビューした測定値と非常に正確な測定値を使用します。
In the end the answer is that all the rats are running around here
結局のところ、答えは、すべてのネズミがここを走り回っているということです
His brain behaves as if he cares about the pie of some parts
彼の脳は、あたかも自分の一部のパイを気にしているかのように動作します
Why is it important to be there
なぜそこにいることが重要なのでしょうか
This is of course a lot of RESET below us doing this problem
もちろん、この問題を実行している私たちの下では多くのリセットが行われます
But at least this is an interesting phenomenon
しかし、少なくともこれは興味深い現象です
before our eyes
私たちの目の前で
Then this is a show
それでは、これはショーです
You didn't expect such a simple question
こんな単純な質問は予想していませんでした
unexpectedly get such a strange result
予想外にそのような奇妙な結果が得られる
But my conclusion is that when the elemental effect becomes very strong in a large group
しかし、私の結論は、大規模なグループで元素の効果が非常に強くなると、
New Emergy behavior becomes
新しいエマージーの動作は、
These behaviors often require new laws and principles
こうした行動には、多くの場合、新しい法律や原則が必要となります。
That's of course what I'm quoting is the supervisors
もちろん私が引用しているのは監督者の言葉です
PW Anderson
PWアンダーソン
He died two years ago and this is the Nubai Prize winner.
彼は2年前に亡くなりましたが、この人はヌバイ賞の受賞者です。
his proposed book
彼の提案した本
Paper, The More is Different
紙、多ければ多いほど違う
If you go Beyond Nature
自然を超えて行けば
Nature has a Hierarchist Structure Science
自然には階層構造がある 科学
Science does not mean that you are always the most basic
科学は常に最も基本的なものであることを意味するものではありません
You will know all about Science
科学のすべてを知ることができます
layer by layer structure
層ごとの構造
Layer by layer the phenomenon is different
層ごとに現象は異なります
Need different principles to explain
説明するには別の原理が必要
Here are a few questions I just raised
ここで私が提起したいくつかの質問があります
In fact, to tell everyone
実は皆さんにお伝えすると
Turns out what we know isn't quite resolved
私たちが知っていることは完全に解決されていないことが判明
there is always something new
常に何か新しいものがあります
Of course every complex phenomenon
もちろんあらゆる複雑な現象も
Of course I want life science now
もちろん今は生命科学が欲しいです
understand this more and more
これをますます理解してください
This phenomenon occurs in many life sciences
この現象は多くの生命科学で発生します
So it turns out that the simplest phenomenon we understand
つまり、私たちが理解している最も単純な現象は、
it has a new law
新しい法律ができた
new dogma
新的dogma
new principle
新的principle
This is with new rules
これは新しいルールです
That's why of course
だからこそ当然
More and more
だんだん
Those who do physics have to run in
物理学をやっている人は実行する必要があります
research life sciences
生命科学の研究
because this is new rules
これは新しいルールなので
new laws
新しい法律
Then this emerging behavior
そして、この新たな行動は
It's not what we imagined
それは私たちが想像していたものではありません
The stronger the force
力が強いほど
I just talked about scientific issues
それから私は科学的な問題について話しました
If you think about it, think about human beings
それを考えるなら、人間について考えてください
All the problems I just mentioned have arisen
先ほど述べたすべての問題が発生しています
Our role is also getting stronger
私たちの役割もさらに強化されています
The role of people and people in today's world
今日の世界における人と人の役割
And the range distance is getting stronger and stronger
そして射程距離はますます強くなります
Of course it's because of the phone
もちろん電話のせいです
this Internet problem
このインターネットの問題
we can talk to people very far
私たちはとても遠くにいる人々と話すことができます
Many people act at the same time
多くの人が同時に行動する
and it's very powerful
そしてそれはとても強力です
what does long mean
長いとはどういう意味ですか
It's just that you have a lot of leftover information
残っている情報がたくさんあるだけです
very fast
とても早い
information is power
情報は力です
I didn't say it just now
今言ったんじゃないよ
In fact, the scope of the cowherd just mentioned
実際、先ほど述べた牛飼いの範囲は、
all mean the same thing
どれも同じ意味です
The force we are talking about is between the residual information
私たちが話している力は、残留情報の間にあるものです。
information interacts with each other
情報は相互に影響し合う
These data will generate a large
これらのデータは大規模なデータを生成します。
new human activity
新しい人類の活動
There will be many new behaviors appearing
たくさんの新しい動作が登場します
in human society
人間社会では
This is something we haven't encountered before
これは私たちがこれまで遭遇したことのないものです
Because previous human information
過去の人間情報なので
are limited to small
小さいものに限られます
it's different now
今は違います
completely changed the human
人間を完全に変えた
This activity is actually
実はこの活動は、
So now sociology has become very interesting
社会学はとても面白くなりました
It is no longer the old sociology
それはもはや古い社会学ではありません
Because the emerging behavior may become a
なぜなら、新たな行動は次のようなものになる可能性があるからです。
quite important phenomenon
かなり重要な現象
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
ok then thank you very much
わかりました、それではありがとうございました
Such a brilliant speech by Academician Li
李学者の素晴らしいスピーチ
We are now open to ask questions
ご質問を受け付けております
The first 10 viewers who asked questions
質問をした最初の 10 人の視聴者
Chinese medicine hospital is ready
漢方病院が完成しました
a beautiful gift
美しい贈り物
for everyone
すべての人のために
so please don't be shy
だから恥ずかしがらないでください
if there is a problem
問題がある場合
please raise your hand
手を挙げてください
so hands can
だから手でもできる
The staff can hand over the microphone to everyone
スタッフが全員にマイクを渡すことができます
this one here first
まずこれをここに
The strong force of the teacher
先生の強い力
Is the strong force you mentioned related to the injury we usually talk about?
あなたが言った強い力は、私たちが普段話している怪我と関係がありますか？
heel injury
かかとの怪我
right
右
Injury is not necessarily related to force
怪我は必ずしも力によるものとは限らない
But the injury refers to its degree of freedom or its degree of chaos
しかし、傷害とは、その自由度または混乱の度合いを指します。
What I just said has something to do with injuries.
私が今言ったことは怪我と関係があります。
But it's not directly related to force
でもそれは武力とは直接関係ない
Strong force does not necessarily mean serious injury
強い力が必ずしも重傷を意味するわけではない
Sometimes the strong force is what you think should be imagined
時には強い力を想像すべきだと思うこともあります
For example, two cushions are kept together
たとえば、クッションを 2 つ並べると、
can't run around
走り回れない
So the injury is reduced
それで怪我も軽減される
right
右
But if there are many times
でも何度もあるなら
Not necessarily when it comes out with a new feature
新しい機能がリリースされたときとは限りません
So this has nothing to do with the injury directly.
したがって、これは怪我とは直接関係ありません。
I don't know what you just said is also an interesting question
今何と言ったか分かりませんが、これも興味深い質問です
injury related to injury
怪我に関連した怪我
you know
ほら
With such a strong force, the injury may actually be less
このような強い力であれば、実際には怪我は少ないかもしれません
Because of yours, some of our little Internet celebrities are very powerful
あなたのおかげで、私たちの小さなインターネット有名人は非常に強力です
How much does an Internet celebrity talk about and how many people it immediately affects
インターネットの有名人がどれだけ話題にし、それが即座に何人の人に影響を与えるか
Many people followed it, so it actually hurt less
多くの人がそれに従ったので、実際には傷つきは少なくなりました
ok second place at the end
はい、最後に2位
Professor Li, I just heard that
李先生、今聞きました。
There are electronic teams formed and then there is a coordination mechanism
電子チームが形成され、調整メカニズムが存在します。
tidal conduction
潮伝導
Tide guide phenomenon, then I would like to ask about this coordination mechanism
タイドガイド現象、ではこの調整機構についてお聞きしたいのですが
It is also seen that when the electronic team is confined to one place
電子チームが 1 つの場所に限定されている場合にも、
It may not be able to form a tidal guide, so is there any way for us to get from this state
潮汐ガイドを形成できない可能性がありますが、この状態から抜け出す方法はありますか?
use it as a coordinated Is there a way to make a coordinated mechanism
連携機構として使用する 連携機構を作る方法はありますか
Then let it return to a tidal state like this
そして、このような潮の状態に戻します
That is how we observe this coordinated phenomenon
それがこの調整現象を観察する方法です
That's my problem, thanks
それは私の問題です、ありがとう
Of course there are many ways to deal with this phenomenon
もちろん、この現象に対処する方法はたくさんあります
I didn't have time to talk about it just now because high tide conduction is complicated.
高潮伝導は複雑なので、それについて話す時間がありませんでした。
but it actually
しかし実際には
So this theory is now accepted by most people
したがって、この理論は現在ほとんどの人に受け入れられています
I found that a Couper Pair has been formed but there is no guidance
クーパーペアが形成されていることがわかりましたが、ガイダンスがありません
Just like the experimental results I showed just now, the results are very certain.
先ほど示した実験結果と同様に、結果は非常に確実です。
It already has a Couper Pair but it doesn't have a coupe
すでにクーパーペアがありますが、クーペはありません
But how to become a coordination problem is very complicated
しかし、どのように調整問題が発生するかは非常に複雑です
what you wrote is a good question
あなたが書いたことは良い質問です
That's what everyone is thinking about
それは誰もが考えていることです
just now I didn't have time to explain
今、説明する時間がありませんでした
just like dancing
まるで踊るように
just use this dance to explain
このダンスを使って説明してください
For example, at the beginning there is music here
たとえば、最初にここに音楽があります
some jumping over here
ここに飛び越える人もいる
below there are some over there
下にもあそこにもいくつかあります
they may not be coordinated
調整されていない可能性があります
have been inconsistent
一貫性がありませんでした
because he can dance his
彼は自分で踊れるから
he dances his
彼は自分のダンスを踊る
But if a multiplayer jump starts in the middle
ただし、マルチプレイヤーのジャンプが途中から始まる場合は、
When everyone dances together and connects together
みんなで踊って繋がったら
that becomes more and more coordinated
それはますます調整されます
Not enough questions don't bump into each other
質問が足りないとお互いがぶつからない
push each other up
お互いを押し上げ合う
Then start coordinating
それからコーディネートを始めます
In fact, this human being has many things
実はこの人間には色々なものがある
For example, if you take a picture, everyone takes random pictures
たとえば、あなたが写真を撮ると、みんながランダムに写真を撮ります。
When many people shoot together, after a while it becomes very coordinated
多くの人が一緒に撮影すると、しばらくすると非常に調和したものになります
This is the evidence of many experiments
これは多くの実験の証拠です
is the coordination
コーディネートです
But in the real material
しかし、実際の資料では
how do you coordinate
コーディネートはどうしていますか
It's actually quite difficult
実はかなり難しいんです
It's a matter of directing the coordination
コーディネートのディレクションの問題です
has always been an important issue
常に重要な問題であった
But pretty much hasn't been figured out a good way
しかし、あまり良い方法は見つかっていません
Then we coordinate when we see coordination
それではコーディネートを見かけたらコーディネートしてみます
uncoordinated uncoordinated
調整されていない
But some people will become more coordinated at low temperature
しかし、低温の方が協調性が高まる人もいます
Uncoordinated high temperature
調整されていない高温
It's about business
ビジネスの話です
it's about business
それはビジネスのことです
this is another question
これは別の質問です
ok the gentleman is in the middle
オーケー、紳士が真ん中にいる
Hello Yueshi
こんにちはユエシ
I just saw you mentioned the experiment you conducted
あなたが行った実験について言及したのを見たところです
Just watch a VR with a mouse
マウスでVRを見るだけ
Then there is control over him
そうすれば彼をコントロールできるようになる
not me doing the experiment
私の実験ではありません
That's someone else's experiment
それは他人の実験です
just like China
中国と同じように
We experimented with a professor
教授と一緒に実験してみました
It's a mouse with a little microscope on its head
頭に小さな顕微鏡が付いたネズミです
in that mini school
あのミニスクールで
micro school
マイクロスクール
mini micro school
ミニマイクロスクール
I'm curious
私は興味がある
In the end you concluded that
最終的にあなたはこう結論付けました
He is also in a critical state
彼も危篤状態にある
Then his parameters
次に彼のパラメータ
looks like
のように見える
Other parameters
その他のパラメータ
The parameters of the belly of that picture
その写真のお腹のパラメータ
What is the x-axis and y-axis
X軸とY軸とは何ですか
Then how to conclude that
ではどうやって結論づけるかというと、
he is in a critical state
彼は危篤状態にある
I think this is quite interesting
これはかなり面白いと思います
here
ここ
you say
あなたは言う
no
いいえ
Because we're going to put the experimental numbers
実験的な数字を載せるから
I just didn't have time to talk
ただ話す時間がなかっただけです
you asked
あなたは尋ねました
i can talk
話せる
is the number we put in the experiment
は実験で使用した数値です
use a model to
モデルを使用して
fit it
それに合う
In fact, the same as before
実は以前と同じように
Anyway, you gave me the experimental data
とにかく実験データをくれた
I use the simplest model
最も単純なモデルを使用します
I want to get the simplest model
最も単純なモデルを取得したい
go fit it
フィットしに行ってください
can you fit
フィットできますか
The answer is that it can fit well
答えは「うまくフィットする」です
Then I can find a model
そしたらモデルが見つかるよ
Then I ask the model now
それではモデルさんに聞いてみます
if i have model
モデルがいるなら
I can use it as a physical model
物理モデルとして使用できます
I can put assuming a hypothetical temperature
仮定の温度を仮定して置くことができます
Put the fake temperature in
偽の温度を入力してください
I'll do the math
計算してみます
Various phenomena in this model
このモデルにおけるさまざまな現象
then i realize
それから私は気づきました
how can it have a phase
どのように位相を持つことができますか
as if distinguishing
まるで区別しているかのように
Of course it doesn't really look like
もちろん実際には似ていない
Because it's not a big system
大したシステムではないので
For example, we only have 8 or 90
たとえば、8 または 90 しかありません。
Neuroblasts are not millions
ニューロンは数百万ではない
so few systems
システムが非常に少ない
But at least we see a big
しかし、少なくとも私たちは大きなことを見ています
This is the PIC
これがPICです
that's what we figured out
それが私たちが考え出したことです
Its slope is the largest here
ここが一番傾斜が大きい
It is also the largest near T.1
T.1付近では最大規模でもある
so this is weird
だからこれは奇妙だ
this seems to be a coincidence
これは偶然のようです
because there is so much space
スペースがたくさんあるので
it can be found here
ここで見つけることができます
T.1 is the experimental data
T.1は実験データです
Come in fitting is used to mention
フィッティングをしてポイントを上げるために使用してください
When we extend it
延長すると
We found out why the experimental data is not here
実験データがここにない理由がわかりました
Why must it be here on the biggest peak
なぜここが最大の峰にあるのだろうか
Why are you at Dafeng?
なぜ大豊にいるのですか？
Actually it's not necessary
実際には必要ありません
this is a very strange thing
これはとても奇妙なことです
Of course I'm talking about this
もちろんこれについて話しています
we're not the first to do it
私たちがそれを最初にやったわけではありません
What people do is more fine-grained data
人々が行うのはより詳細なデータです
They also found this phenomenon
彼らはこの現象も発見しました
This phenomenon becomes very special
この現象は非常に特殊になります
Why do these mouse neurons
なぜこれらのマウスのニューロンは
From what we see he likes to be on this peak
私たちが見るところによると、彼はこの頂上にいるのが好きだそうです
In fact, he can be in any
実際、彼はどんな状況にもなれる
Why does he have to be on this peak
なぜ彼はこの頂上にいなければならないのか
Of course this is the most important question
もちろんこれが最も重要な質問です
Physically speaking
物理的に言えば
Such a simple model is not very complicated
このような単純なモデルはそれほど複雑ではありません
I just said that in fact
実はそう言っただけです
Mostly like the flock of birds
ほとんど鳥の群れのようです
looks so complicated
とても複雑に見えます
but they can predict very well
しかし彼らは非常によく予測することができます
In fact they can also do dynamic
実際、ダイナミックな操作も可能です
prediction of time
時間的prediction
all work
すべての仕事
just can't figure it out
ただそれが理解できない
Model Actually, I think if you know this
モデル 実はこれをご存知の方はいると思います
Chinese and American professors already know
中国とアメリカの教授はすでに知っています
That is the classical Heisenberg model
それが古典的なハイゼンベルクモデルです
That work can't believe why he works so well
あの作品はなぜ彼があんなにうまくいくのか信じられない
and things in nature
そして自然界のもの
Then why does he work so well
では、なぜ彼はそんなにうまく仕事ができるのでしょうか
surprise
サプライズ
the lady
女性
Basic This Electron to Thermal Group
基本的なこの電子から熱群へ
And finally to the animal group, the human group
そして最後に動物のグループ、人間のグループへ
Then we often use
それから私たちはよく使います
you from the couple effect
カップル効果のあなた
to this highest this
この最高にこれ
The collective behavior you are talking about
あなたが話している集団行動
There are some in the middle called Cui Xing
真ん中にはCui Xingと呼ばれるものがあります
also steady state
定常状態も
Can you use a very simple sentence between this
この間に非常に簡単な文を使っていただけますか
string it on force
力を入れて弦を張る
From a point of view of force
力の観点から見ると
Look at such a collective behavior
こういう集団行動を見てください
forget about it
気にしないで
The force must be present to have a non-transition
非遷移を実現するには力が存在する必要があります
Without force, of course there won't be
力がなければもちろんありません
That non transition from one boundary to another
それはある境界から別の境界への移行ではありません
Actually nothing has changed, right?
実際には何も変わっていないですよね？
A water molecule is a water molecule, a gas
水の分子は水分子であり、気体です
Become liquid again, become solid again, become ice again
また液体になって、また固体になって、また氷になって
The thing has not changed, the composition has not changed, but its shape can change
ものは変わらない、構成は変わらないが、その形は変わる可能性がある
Did the force change or did not change
力は変化しましたか、それとも変化しませんでしたか
In principle you can write down a force
原理的には力を書き留めることができます
Especially with the current calculation method, you can calculate
特に現在の計算方法では、次のように計算できます。
But here, of course, is what I just said
しかし、もちろん、ここで私が今言ったことです。
This is a question of statistical body thermodynamics
これは統計的な身体熱力学の問題です
Because the exchange of injury and energy changes the harmony of each other
傷とエネルギーの交換が互いの調和を変えるから
you can come out in different shapes
さまざまな形で出てくることができます
Of course now I know this
もちろん今はそれを知っています
That is the simplest case more complicated
それは最も単純なケースですが、より複雑です
many complex traps
多くの複雑な罠
Like I didn't have time to talk just now
今は話す時間がなかったようです
Our model is actually related to last year's Nobel Prize
私たちのモデルは実は昨年のノーベル賞に関連しています
This is called the Spin Glass Model.
これをスピングラスモデルと呼びます。
with last year's nobel prize winner
昨年のノーベル賞受賞者と
I spoke two or three years late
話すのが2、3年遅れた
two nobel laureates
二人のノーベル賞受賞者
Everything I do is related to this
私のやることはすべてこれに関係しています
This is Zhixuan Glass Model
これはZhixuanガラスモデルです
that's... that's more complicated
それは...もっと複雑です
Then it is often said here that there is no...
それから、ここではよく言われるのですが、それはありません...
that is not to say
それは言うことではありません
You said that even a force can be negative energy
力だって負のエネルギーになり得るって君は言った
That's what I've been wanting to...
それが私が望んでいたものです...
The emphasis is that the system is different
強調したいのはシステムが違うということ
The force is different
勢いが違う
ingredients if different
成分が違う場合
You may have many new phenomena
新しい現象がたくさん起こるかもしれません
not what you thought
あなたが思っていたこととは違います
Especially when the force is stronger
特に力が強い場合
more complexity
より複雑な
we already know this
私たちはすでにこれを知っています
more and more clear
ますます明確になる
It has more new behaviors that you can't imagine will come out
想像もつかないような新しい動作がさらに登場します
This phenomenon is more and more
この現象はますます増えています
But I think in the life sciences
しかし、生命科学の分野では、
It's been happening for a long time
それは長い間起こっている
I have had this for a long time
私はこれを長い間持っています
existing problems
既存の問題
because of the life sciences
生命科学のせいで
In fact, I think it's all strongly correlated.
実際、これらはすべて強い相関関係があると思います。
It's all a powerful system at work
すべては強力なシステムとして機能しています
So it actually has a large
したがって、実際には大きな
Many emerging phenomena
多くの新たな現象
I still don't understand
まだわかりません
But that's the direction of research
でもそれが研究の方向性だよ
But this is no universal theory
しかし、これは普遍的な理論ではありません
This is actually to tell you that
これは実際にあなたにそれを伝えるためです
No Z theory
Z理論はありません
good lady in the back
後ろにいる良い女性
Hello Mr. Li
こんにちは、リーさん
It's the picture on the left
左の写真です
It's actually quite interesting
実はかなり面白いんです
So my question is
それで私の質問は
Here with the whole population
ここに全国民とともに
Nuron's threshold
Nuron のしきい値
does it matter
それは重要ですか
Because Nuron's firing exceeds the threshold
ニューロンの発射が閾値を超えているため
Is it 0101?
0101ですか？
That is we made a simplification
つまり単純化したのです
The easiest thing for a physical person to do
肉体的な人間にとって最も簡単なこと
When you see a cow, turn it into a ball
牛を見たらボールに変えてください
leave it alone
ほっといて
But the same thing happened to us
しかし、同じことが私たちにも起こりました
Of course what we do is in our Poverty Paper
もちろん、私たちが行っていることは貧困文書に記載されています
Is to use different Threshold to show
別のしきい値を使用して表示することです
no relevance
関連性がない
at least within reason
少なくとも合理的な範囲内で
there is no correlation
相関関係はありません
Thanks
ありがとう
THIS ANSWER IS FULL AND VERY ROBUS
この回答は完全かつ非常に堅牢です
This is what we most want to amplify in Paper
これが私たちが Paper で最も強調したいことです
very strange
非常に奇妙な
Why so ROBUS
なぜそんなにロバスなのか
This is also a strange thing
これも不思議な事ですね
lady in front
前の女性
Thank you teacher for sharing
先生、シェアしてくれてありがとう
I have a question
質問があります
I'm sorry, I'm not learning at all
ごめんなさい、全然勉強してないです
But in terms of deepening
しかし深化という点では
You mentioned that when you danced just now
さっき踊ってる時に言ってたよね
There are times when there is not much pairing
ペアリングが少ない時もある
Then I also talk about it in class
それから授業でも話します
When there are encounters with some electronic teams that are not paired
ペアになっていない電子チームが存在する場合
he will rob others
彼は他人から物を奪うだろう
We electron orbital group two two electrons
私たちは電子軌道グループ 2 つの 2 つの電子
Of course when they rob
もちろん強盗するときは
Grab him and release him to become Free Radicals
彼を捕まえて解放し、フリーラジカルにしよう
like say
言うように
The leaves of the tooth iron become iron nuggets
歯鉄の葉は鉄塊になる
So iron becomes Free Radical
つまり鉄はフリーラジカルになる
It can't be a pair
ペアにはなれないよ
It will do Chain Reaction
連鎖反応を起こします
Damage caused by grinding
研削による損傷
and then finally cause some
そして最終的にはいくつかの原因を引き起こします
Mutual or casino tool issues
相互またはカジノツールの問題
But when you talk about it
でも、それについて話すと、
Squeeze it out into a UFO attitude
UFOのような姿勢に絞り出す
seems positive
ポジティブに見える
These two are a bit
この二人はちょっと
Very special and comparative explanation
非常に特殊な比較説明
The UFO is not where it becomes Free Radical
UFOはフリーラジカルになる場所ではない
in fact limit it
実際にはそれを制限する
only put that
それだけを置く
I just didn't have time to talk
ただ話す時間がなかっただけです
Inside Vortex
インサイドボルテックス
Is there any paired electrons
対電子はありますか
it won't be paired
ペアリングされません
Each has its own electricity inside
それぞれの内部には独自の電気が備わっています
so it puts all those extra pairs of electrons in there
余分な電子対をすべてそこに置きます
The key is like that
鍵ってそういうものだよ
then don't run around
それなら走り回らないでください
just mess with others
他人とめちゃくちゃにするだけ
how smart do you see
どのくらい賢いと思いますか
Your Radical
あなたの急進派
if you make it this far
ここまでできたら
you can cure
あなたは治すことができます
right
右
Radical
ラジカル
don't let it run around
走り回らせないでください
and instead of us putting it in
私たちがそれを入れる代わりに
We rot it becomes a result of nature
私たちは腐ります、それは自然の結果になります
it will rot automatically
自動的に腐ってしまう
don't run around
走り回らないでください
Why
なぜ
because it runs around
走り回るから
The resulting energy will increase and destroy the entire tire
結果として生じるエネルギーは増加し、タイヤ全体を破壊します
The whole tire is so big, so it will be limited to a certain place
タイヤ全体が大きいので、場所が限られてしまいます
So radical can't rap
過激すぎるとラップができない
But in life science, it will come out to do chain reaction
しかし、生命科学では連鎖反応を起こすものが出てきます。
Yes, it won't run out, so there are certain ways to deal with this problem on its side
はい、なくなることはないので、この問題を解決する特定の方法があります
So it automatically solves it without this
したがって、これがなくても自動的に解決されます
This is of course Apricotium nano, don't talk about the important place
もちろんこれはアプリコチウムナノです、大事な場所については話さないでください
This is automatic, this nature will automatically give you a solution
これは自動的に行われます。この性質により、自動的に解決策が提供されます。
It is this electronic tire that automatically gives you a solution, which solves this problem
この問題を解決する解決策を自動的に提供するのがこの電子タイヤです。
And the solution is very beautiful, very beautiful solution to this problem
そして、その解決策は非常に美しく、この問題に対する非常に美しい解決策です
No human intervention is required at all
人間の介入はまったく必要ありません
It tells you that what we now prove is the solution of the natural state
それは、私たちが今証明しているのは自然状態の解決策であることを示しています。
So it's not that we invent new solutions, it doesn't, it's just that after it's poured out
つまり、私たちが新しい解決策を発明するわけではなく、そうではなく、単にそれが注ぎ出された後であるだけです
We can fully explain this solution
この解決策を完全に説明できます
Then this solution will tell you in the experiment
この解決策は実験でわかります
Life science has a chain reaction, which is negative
ライフサイエンスには連鎖反応があり、それはマイナスです
Life science has a...
生命科学には...
It has no pre-reaction because it cannot come out
出ないので事前反応なし
it's confined inside, it can't come out
中に閉じ込められて出られない
this is a very special place
ここはとても特別な場所です
This is what Mr. Murray just said
これはマレー氏が今言ったことです
your question is very good
あなたの質問はとても良いです
But there is an automatic way
しかし、自動的な方法があります
I think the human body can do it automatically.
人間の体は自動的にそれを行うことができると思います。
How to control Ratical
ラティカルのコントロール方法
we have three here
ここには3つあります
We are behind first, and then the second is here
私たちは最初に遅れをとっていて、次に2番目がここにいます
Thank you academician for your speech
学者さん、講演ありがとうございました
Then I have a few questions I want to ask the academician
それから、学者に聞きたいことがいくつかあります
The first one is whether all substances
1つ目は、すべての物質が
There will be critical phenomena
重大な現象が起こるだろう
Either the temperature is too high or the temperature is too low
温度が高すぎるか、温度が低すぎるかのどちらかです
It's just a matter of whether I can measure it or I can't measure it
測れるか測れないかだけの問題
The second little problem is
2番目の小さな問題は、
Because you just mentioned the collective behavior of humans
なぜならあなたは今人間の集団行動について言及したからです
seems to be related to what you just mentioned
あなたが今言ったことに関連しているようです
Clustering may be somewhat conceptual
クラスタリングはいくぶん概念的なものかもしれません
Then my question is to ask
それから私の質問はこうです
Let things like war, plague, or famine
戦争、疫病、飢餓などは放っておいてください
Is that also a so-called critical phenomenon?
それもいわゆる臨界現象なのでしょうか？
The third question is to ask
3 番目の質問は次のとおりです。
Is that as long as a certain amount is reached?
一定の金額に達していれば可能なのでしょうか？
That means there is only one bird today that we may not see
つまり、今日見られない可能性のある鳥は1羽だけです
That might be ten birds and I might not even see them
それは私が会えないかもしれない10羽の鳥かもしれません
But if I accumulate ten thousand birds
でも一万羽貯めたら
can i see this
これを見てもいいですか
such a group phenomenon
そういう集団現象
It's like the war just now or the plague or the famine
まるで今の戦争か疫病か飢餓のようだ
Is it that these events will eventually happen in the history of mankind?
これらの出来事は人類の歴史の中で最終的に起こるのでしょうか？
It's just that the amount we accumulate
ただ積み上げた分だけ
Or a certain amount of accumulation has not been reached
または一定の蓄積量に達していない
So it just happens early or it happens late
つまり、それは早く起こるか遅く起こるだけです
Thanks
ありがとう
This question is the hardest to answer
この質問は答えるのが最も難しいです
This question is very interesting
この質問はとても興味深いです
not this question is a very good question
この質問はとても良い質問ではありません
questions we've been thinking about
私たちが考えてきた質問
but it's hard to answer
でも答えるのは難しい
Because my problem is that our analysis now
私の問題は、今の分析です
Our previous analysis method is different
これまでの分析方法とは異なります
we don't have enough data
十分なデータがありません
Your problem now is with this data
あなたの問題はこのデータにあります
if we do physics
物理学をやるなら
That is to say, I don't like to think about philosophical problems casually.
つまり、私は哲学的な問題について気軽に考えるのが好きではありません。
Then we become philosophers
そうすれば我々は哲学者になる
Physicist is what I want to see the data
データを見たいのは物理学者
what kind of data
どのようなデータですか
I can analyze it like this
こんな感じで分析できます
Is this the zero line?
これがゼロラインでしょうか？
Is your war border zero
戦争の国境はゼロですか
that might not be like
それはそうではないかもしれない
because of aggressiveness
攻撃性のせいで
like i think everyone
私がみんな思うように
our DNA may have
私たちの DNA はそうかもしれない
It's a bit troublesome now
もうちょっと面倒です
this is i'm not sure yet
これはまだわかりません
It's a phenomenon of how many groups
それは何グループかの現象です
Or he already had this idea
あるいは、彼はすでにこのアイデアを持っていた
That’s what I said group is different from Emerging
それが私が言ったグループはエマージングとは違うということです
group is a phenomenon
集団というのは現象である
But he is not necessarily Emerging's Behavior
しかし、彼は必ずしもエマージングの行動ではありません
OK, as long as he already has
OK、彼がすでに持っている限り
Say you train the army
あなたが軍隊を訓練しているとします
Everyone shoots and hits, right?
みんな撃って当たるじゃないですか。
He trains well by himself
彼は一人でよくトレーニングします
that gathers them
彼らを集めるのは
they also do the same thing
彼らも同じことをします
He has no Emerging behavior
彼には新たな行動はありません
His Behavior is the original
彼の行動はオリジナルです
each individual
各個人
and then just get together
それから一緒に集まってください
it's two different things
それは2つの異なるものです
What I just said is that it has a completely new phenomenon
私が今言ったのは、まったく新しい現象があるということです
Like the superconducting invention just now, two batteries
先ほどの超電導発明のように、電池が２つ
should be mutually exclusive
相互に排他的である必要があります
it does not exclude
それは除外しません
Actually I didn't have time to talk just now
実は今話す時間がなかったんだ
its just the battery and
それは単なるバッテリーであり、
A battery in the superconducting state is not the original battery
超電導状態のバッテリーは本来のバッテリーではありません
You know that batteries and superconductivity are two different things
電池と超電導は別物だということはご存知でしょう
this is totally different
これは全く違います
this is completely new
全く新しいです
If you use the old concept, you're screwed
古い概念を使用するとダメになります
So I kept talking about new phenomena
それで私は新しい現象について話し続けました
New Law new this understanding
新しい法律、新しいこの理解
not the old way
古いやり方ではない
This point is that physics has begun to understand
この点は物理学が理解し始めているということです
I think some subjects
いくつかの科目があると思います
Still think it comes from reductionism
それは還元主義から来ていると今でも思っている
can solve everything
すべてを解決できる
I think of course it is a bit difficult
もちろん少し難しいとは思いますが
There are many problems with reductionism
還元主義には多くの問題がある
May be no way to use
使い道がないかもしれない
You can't use the reduction method
減額方法は使えません
use each individual
一人ひとりを利用する
I know the genes now
もう遺伝子はわかった
strong association, your genome
あなたのゲノムとの強い関連性
Although I know all the genes are sorted
遺伝子の順序はすべてわかっているのに
It's not necessarily impossible to understand genetics
遺伝学を理解することは必ずしも不可能ではない
because they are really strongly correlated
なぜならそれらは本当に強い相関関係があるからです
it has many new phenomena
多くの新しい現象があります
It's not us, you used to know everyone
それは私たちではありません、あなたは皆を知っていました
I think we understand this too
これは私たちも理解していると思います
But it's not unusual in physics
でも物理学では珍しいことではない
so we've seen too much of this
私たちはこれをあまりにも多く見てきました
It's not as simple as you thought
あなたが思っているほど単純ではありません
very strong
とても強い
but i answered your question
しかし私はあなたの質問に答えました
Because I don't remember any other questions from you.
あなたからの他の質問を覚えていないからです。
How many birds do you want
何羽の鳥が欲しいですか
That's also good question
それも良い質問ですね
Same problem as coherence just now
先ほどのコヒーレンスと同じ問題
How much is the answer I don't know
答えはいくらですかわかりません
You have seen it with very little
ほんの少ししか見せていないのに、もう見てしまったのですね
As I said just now, I only used seventy or eighty neurons
先ほども言いましたが、ニューロンは 70 ～ 80 個しか使っていません
I can already see that it looks like a cretial state
すでに限界状態にあることがわかります
But I dare not say it is in the cretial state
しかし、それが危機的な状態にあるとはあえて言いません
because it is not infinity
無限ではないから
But its behavior has already begun to appear
しかし、その行動はすでに現れ始めています
But from the mathematical definition
しかし数学的定義からすると
you can't be so rigid by definition
定義上、そこまで厳格になることはできません
but physically
しかし物理的に
it behaves like
それは次のように動作します
already too close
すでに近すぎます
already makes me a little uneasy
すでに少し不安になっています
Actually I see it turns out to be unsettling
実際、それは不安になることがわかります
I don't know why there is such a result
なぜそのような結果になるのか分かりません
then we thought we were doing it wrong
それから私たちはそれが間違っていたと思いました
So we've been researching
それで私たちは研究してきました
Now with more data
より多くのデータが得られるようになりました
It's an uneducated number that gives us more data
これは、より多くのデータを提供する根拠のない数字です
the answer is the same
答えは同じです
This is of course very strange
これはもちろん非常に奇妙です
very interesting question
とても興味深い質問
But this I don't know
でもこれは分からない
don't need a lot
たくさんは必要ありません
OK
OK
But it takes a lot to change infinity
しかし、無限を変えるには多くのことが必要です
Otherwise you can't see infinity
そうしないと無限が見えない
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Just this one
これだけ
in the middle
途中で
please raise your hand
手を挙げてください
I can get you the microphone
マイクをお届けします
good
良い
Hello, Li Yuanshi
こんにちは、李源石さん
just now i mentioned
今私が言いました
There will be a special coherence between Cooprope
Cooprope の間には特別な一貫性が存在します。
i want to ask
聞きたいです
synchronous coordination
同期調整
Is this phenomenon immediate or is it a gradual behavior
この現象は即時的なものですか、それとも徐々に起こるものですか?
The BCX theory is immediacy
BCX 理論は即時性です
so its resistance becomes 0
そのため抵抗は0になります
No resistance to 0 without peers
仲間がいないと0に抵抗がない
As soon as it reaches below tc the resistance is 0
tc 以下に達するとすぐに抵抗は 0 になります。
Not 0.001
0.001ではありません
It's not 0.001 either
0.001でもないよ
it is 0
それは0です
OK
OK
no resistance
抵抗がない
So the question you just mentioned is that the experimental data is Mangeli
つまり、あなたが今言った質問は、実験データがマンゲリであるということです。
But high temperature superconductivity is different.
しかし、高温超伝導は異なります。
The high-temperature superconductivity mentioned just now is a bit embarrassing.
先ほどの高温超伝導というのはちょっと恥ずかしいですね。
Companionship and pairing are two different temperatures
仲間関係とペアリングは異なる温度です
look first
まず見てください
OK
OK
Then this is a different temperature
それから、これは温度が違います
Pair first, then tune
まずペアリングしてから調整してください
But thinking about it now so it's more negative
でも今考えるともっとネガティブです
you can tell it's uneven
不均一であることがわかります
its the same strip , its this dancing room
同じストリップ、このダンスルーム
Not one hall, many small halls, many highlands, different
一つのホールではなく、たくさんの小さなホール、たくさんの高地、さまざまな
different place
違う場所
Everybody's dancing over there, as you can imagine
ご想像のとおり、あそこではみんなが踊っています
If there is such a scene, this dance must be very exciting
こんなシーンがあったらこのダンスはきっと盛り上がるはず
How can I dance without being strong or...
力強くないのにどうやって踊ればいいのか…
that's complicated
それは複雑です
Then this, you can imagine, that is like Gao Wenchao brain
それから、これはご想像のとおり、ガオ・ウェンチャオの脳のようなものです
a bit complicated
少し複雑な
more challenges
さらなる挑戦
But it doesn't have to be the same
しかし、同じである必要はありません
It's just a pair
ただのペアです
So it, but the theory of BCS is that pairing is the same
それはそうですが、BCS の理論ではペアリングは同じです
ok here miss here
はい、ここをお見逃しなく
Hello teacher, I don't know if there is...
こんにちは、先生、あるかどうかわかりませんが...
Is there any chance to listen to the teacher's introduction
先生の紹介を聞く機会はありますか
The video that just didn't have time to play
再生する時間がなかったビデオ
Thanks
ありがとう
Is that... blessed?
それは...恵まれていますか？
that...
それか...
how to go back
戻る方法
that...that will...
それは...それは...
The one I put...
私が入れたのは…
it's here
ここにあります
OK here
ここでOK
Like this time he put a...
今回のように彼は...
liquid hazard
液体の危険性
That thing just now was a liquid hazard
さっきのあれは液体危険物だった
put that superconductor in
その超電導体を入れてください
put liquid harm
液体に害を与える
Then he put a magnet on it
それから彼はその上に磁石を置きました
Look at him now...
今彼を見てください...
he wants to push him
彼は彼を押したいと思っています
he can push
彼は押すことができる
no middle...
中間はありません...
I wanted to do an experiment for you guys
皆さんのために実験をしてみたいと思いました
but...
しかし...
I guess the experiment didn't see clearly
実験ではよく見えなかったと思います
it shines more clearly
より鮮明に輝きます
it pushes it
それはそれを押します
it didn't touch
触れなかった
That magnet is floating
その磁石は浮いている
real suspension
リアルサスペンション
look at its invisible hands
その見えざる手を見てください
yes catch this
はい、これを捕まえてください
but it's not tight enough now
でも今はまだきつくない
so it pushes it down a little bit
それで少し押し下げます
The magnetic field lines go in and exceed how many
磁力線は何本入り、何本を超えますか
Then it can be lifted
そしたら持ち上げられるよ
You see such a heavy whole block
とても重いブロック全体が見えます
Magnets can pull it up
磁石で引き上げることができる
then it is here
それならここです
put this in too
これも入れて
take this
これを取る
It's actually right here in the glove
それは実際にこの手袋の中にあります
That temperature is what I just said
その温度は私が今言ったことです
liquid hi is -200 degrees
液体ハイは-200度です
It's minus 200 degrees
マイナス200度だよ
so around 200 degrees
だから200度くらい
It must wear gloves
手袋を着用する必要があります
Otherwise it will show here
それ以外の場合はここに表示されます
It puts an orange on top
上にオレンジを乗せます
it doesn't matter
それは問題ではありません
still heavy enough
まだ十分に重い
Then here it will show
次に、ここに表示されます
it does something special
それは何か特別なことをします
it's magnetic
それは磁気です
its vertical line is uneven
縦の線が不均一です
The inside is different from the outside
内側は外側とは異なります
I want to say that once the lines of magnetic force have a curvature
言いたいのは、磁力線が曲率を持つと
it takes this
これが必要です
Wait a minute and it will put this
ちょっと待ってください、そうすればこれが入れられます
put it on
それを着てください
you see
分かりますか
it won't stop
止まらないよ
such a little effort
そんな小さな努力
push it a little
少し押してください
it keeps spinning on this
これで回転し続ける
can turn for a long time
長時間回転できる
I'm running out of time to show
見せる時間がなくなってきた
this is just for show
これはただの見せ物です
it this
それこの
as long as the position is right
位置が正しい限り
it can go all the way
それはどこまでも行くことができます
because it has no resistance
抵抗がないから
It has a little Energy cost
エネルギーコストが少しかかります
very low is this
これは非常に低いです
When the lines of magnetic force enter and exit
磁力線が出入りするとき
a little bit
若干
it has very little energy
エネルギーが非常に少ないです
to it as a whole
それ全体として
so it lasts a long time
だからそれは長く続く
I just said that the real experiment is not like this
本当の実験はこんなものではないと言っただけです
Seriously, take a superconductor and make a coil
真剣に、超電導体を使ってコイルを作りましょう
Make one, then connect and add battery
作成してバッテリーを接続して追加します
The superconducting current starts running and the battery is removed
超電導電流が流れ始め、バッテリーが取り外される
The current can run here for several years
ここでは数年にわたって電流が流れる可能性がある
It still has energy cost
まだエネルギーコストがかかる
Why? There is radiation
なぜですか? 放射線があるのです
but that's too little
でもそれは少なすぎる
Not important to the whole energy
エネルギー全体にとって重要ではない
so it can be years
だから何年もかかるかもしれない
Then they shut down the experiment
その後彼らは実験を中止した
because there's no need to do it
それをする必要がないから
It means that the resistance is 0
抵抗が0になるということです
In fact, what they want to show is
実際、彼らが見せたいのは、
Otherwise, no one would believe
そうでなければ誰も信じないだろう
Is the resistance really 0?
本当に抵抗は0なのでしょうか？
Is it 10-------16 times
10回ですか-----16回
10 of -------- 25 times issued
10 / -------- 25 回発行
But we now what I just told you
しかし、私たちは今、あなたに今言ったことを
Actually the proof is that it is true 0
実際、その証拠はそれが真実であるということです 0
So it is a quantum number
つまり量子数です
0 is not an hour
0は1時間ではありません
is a real discreet quantum number
は真の離散量子数です
0,1,2,3, that is 0
0、1、2、3、つまり 0
when later many
後で多くの場合
Physics is about finding the first, second, and third of the frame and pillow, which Nanova said
物理学は、フレーム枕の 1 番目、2 番目、3 番目を見つけることです。Nanova 氏はこう言いました。
It is this system that has a certain value
この制度こそ価値がある
This 1 is not 1.001 0.999
この 1 は 1.001 0.999 ではありません
Even a DG can't be wrong
たとえDGであっても間違いはありません
this is quantum
これは量子です
This is the macroscopic quantum
これが巨視的な量子です
Macroscopic quantum like this
巨視的な量子はこんな感じ
such a big thing
そんな大きなこと
all behave
全員が行動する
This is the macroscopic quantum
これが巨視的な量子です
Of course we want to find this at room temperature
もちろん、これは室温で求めたいのですが
Then there's the real room-temperature quantum attitude
次に、実際の室温での量子姿勢です。
Now since the first superconductor is 4 degrees
最初の超伝導体は 4 度なので
absolute temperature 4 degrees
絶対温度4度
How high is it now?
今はどれくらい高いですか？
High temperature superconductors can be pressurized up to 165 degrees
高温超電導体は165度まで加圧可能
Negative pressure is 135 degrees
負圧は135度
But recently a new superconductor has been learned
しかし最近、新しい超伝導体が判明しました。
Very high pressure is tight with sea seat
非常に高圧でシーシートがきつい
Kangkang, that Haocheng came to Shiwen, but this has not been officially accepted
康康、ハオチェンが石文に来たと言うが、これは正式には認められていない
This one still has Zeng Na, and Zeng Chao
曾娜と曾超もいる
But in any case, there is hope, there is no reason why it cannot be higher
しかし、いずれにせよ、希望はあります、それ以上にならない理由はありません
Maybe you don’t need Shiwen, if there is a guide to do it in the icy and snowy winter
極寒の冬にそれを行うためのガイドがあれば、シーウェンは必要ないかもしれません
Yes, during this suddenly everyone thought, if you look at this and think why
そう、この間に突然誰もがこう思いました、これを見て、なぜだろうと考えたら
At that time, everyone was a sensation, and they went to the meeting in the middle of the night
当時はみんな大騒ぎで、夜中に会議に行ったんですよ
Thousands of people, not a few meetings
何千人もの人々、数回の会議
More than 2,000 people were crowded inside
館内には2000人以上の人が詰めかけている
I have no place to go in, I stand at the farthest place to watch
入る場所もなく一番遠い場所に立って眺めている
Everyone uploaded the slideshow in five minutes, and posted what I did and what I did
5分以内に全員がスライドショーをアップロードし、私がやったことややったことを投稿しました
Then this, but why this?
それからこれですが、なぜこれなのでしょうか？
Because when you look at this, you think about the issue of energy, which is too much related to this
というのは、これを見るとエネルギーの問題を考えてしまいますが、それはこれにあまりにも関係しているからです。
With this can solve a big energy problem
これで大きなエネルギー問題が解決できる
but luckily we haven't done it yet
しかし幸いなことに、私たちはまだそれを行っていません
still working hard
まだ頑張っている
ok we have no problem
わかりました、問題ありません
I just heard Li Benshi answer so many questions
李弁士がたくさんの質問に答えるのを聞いたところです
such a wonderful speech
とても素晴らしいスピーチ
Let's applaud again, thank you Li Bianshi
もう一度拍手を送りましょう、ありがとう李ビアンシー
I would like to thank you all for coming here
ここに来てくださった皆さんに感謝したいと思います
Feast of knowledge tonight
今夜の知識の饗宴
Tell you about our next lecture
次回の講義について教えてください
It will be on the evening of Tuesday, December 13th
12月13日火曜日の夕方になります
it's seven o'clock
七時です
We've come to a completely different topic
全く違う話題に来てしまいました
The topic is the encounter between history and criminology
テーマは歴史と犯罪学の出会い
What I want to talk about is the analysis of the theft crime in the middle of the 19th century
私が話したいのは、19世紀半ばの窃盗犯罪の分析です。
So the speaker is researcher Wurenshu
ということで、講演者は研究者のウーレンシューさんです
Is a researcher at the Institute of Modern History of Zhongan Academy of Sciences
中安科学院現代史研究所の研究員です
So the same in
だから同じです
in this venue
この会場で
Please if you are interested
興味があればどうぞ
You can register online
オンラインで登録できます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
have a nice evening everyone
皆さん、良い夜をお過ごしください
Thank you Li Yan
リー・ヤンさん、ありがとう